我认识哈维·丹特 我是他的朋友
I knew Harvey Dent. I was his friend.
这世间恐怕很少人能够像他那样激励我们的心灵
And it will be a very long time before someone inspires us the way he did.
我相信哈维·丹特
I believed in Harvey Dent.
- 帕佛博士 我是中情局的 - 不只他一个人
- Dr. Pavel, I'm CIA.  - He wasn't alone.
- 你不可以带朋友来 - 他们不是我的朋友
- Uh, you don't get to bring friends.  - They are not my friends.
别担心 我不会跟你多收钱
Don't worry, no charge for them.
我干嘛要这两个人？这两人企图绑架那个博士
And why would I want them? They were trying to grab your prize.
他们是那个佣兵的手下
They work for the mercenary.
面罩怪人
The masked man.
贝恩？
Bane?
先带他们上飞机 我来报告
Get them onboard. I'll call it in.
我刚才跟局里提出登机名单
The flight plan I just filed with the agency...
里面有我 我的手下 帕佛博士
...lists me, my men, Dr. Pavel here...
但你们两人中只能选一个
...but only one of you!
先招认的那个人才能留在飞机上
First one to talk gets to stay on my aircraft!
是谁派你们绑架帕佛博士？
Who paid you to grab Dr. Pavel?
你应该不会飞吧
He didn't fly so good!
下一个换谁？
Who wants to try next?
告诉我贝恩的底细
Tell me about Bane!
他为什么戴着面罩？
Why does he wear the mask?
你也未免太忠心耿耿了吧
A lot of loyalty for a hired gun!
他可能在纳闷 为什么把人丢下飞机之前...
Well, perhaps he's wondering why someone would shoot a man...
还要先开枪
...before throwing him out of a plane.
至少你会说话
At least you can talk.
你们是什么人？
Who are you?
我们是谁并不重要
It doesn't matter who we are.
重要的是我们的计划
What matters is our plan.
以前我没戴面罩的时候 没人在意我是谁
No one cared who I was till I put on the mask.
- 扯掉面具你会死吗？ - 会非常痛苦
- If I pull that off, will you die?  - It would be extremely painful.
- 你挺壮的 - 对你而言
- You're a big guy.  - For you.
被逮捕也是你们计划的一部分吗？
Was getting caught part of your plan?
当然
Of course.
帕佛博士拒绝为我们做事 转而投靠你们
Dr. Pavel refused our offer in favor of yours.
- 我们得查明他是否有泄漏机密 - 没有! 我什么也没说!
- We had to find out what he told you...  - Nothing. I said nothing.
恭喜你! 现在你被抓了!
Well, congratulations, you got yourself caught!
- 长官 - 下一步计划是什么？
- Sir?  - Now what's the next step of your master plan?
炸掉这架飞机
Crashing this plane...
不留活口
...with no survivors.
呼叫! 呼叫!
Mayday, Mayday!
你们要对我做什么？放开我
Aah! What you doing to me? Let me out!
不
No!
不 不 不
No, no, no! No!
你不能走 我们其中一人的尸体必须留在飞机残骸里
No! They expect one of us in the wreckage, brother.
我们开战了吗？
Have we started the fire?
没错 战火要升起了
Yes, the fire rises.
冷静点 博士 现在还不到恐惧的时候
Calm down, doctor. Now is not the time for fear.
好戏还在后头
That comes later.
哈维·丹特纪念日虽然不是传统节日
Harvey Dent Day may not be our oldest public holiday...
却是最重要的节日之一
...but we're here tonight because it's one of the most important.
哈维·丹特不遗余力地对抗组织性犯罪
Harvey Dent's uncompromising stand against organized crime...
使得高谭市在这八年间治安逐渐进步
...had made Gotham a safer place than it was at the time of his death, eight years ago.
这个城市造就了历史性的转变
This city has seen a historic turnaround.
每个城市都有犯罪 但高谭市没有组织性犯罪
No city is without crime, but this city is without organized crime because the Dent Act...
归功于丹特法案提供的有效利器让我们能对抗犯罪集团
...gave law enforcement teeth in its fight against the mob.
现在有些人主张废除丹特法案
Now people are talking about repealing the Dent Act...
在此我承诺:"决不让此事发生"
...and to them I say, "Not on my watch."
非常感谢韦恩基金会举办这场晚会
I want to thank the Wayne Foundation for hosting this event.
虽然韦恩先生今晚不能出席 但他的精神与我们同在
I'm told Mr. Wayne couldn't be here tonight. I'm sure he's with us in spirit.
现在我要把麦克风交给一位重量级的...
And now I'm gonna give way to an important voice....
最近有人见过韦恩先生吗？
You ever lay eyes on Wayne at one of these things?
没有 很多年都没人看见他了
No one has. Not in years.
人们曾对一位头戴面具 身穿披风的凶手寄予信任
...people put their faith in a murderous thug in a mask and a cape.
他最终露出了他的真面目
A thug who showed his true nature...
他不但背叛了这位英雄
...when he betrayed the trust of this great man...
还冷血地将他杀害
...and murdered him in cold blood.
小美人 别走那么快
Sweetheart, not so fast with the chow.
- 要来点虾球吗？ - 谢谢
- Shrimp balls?  - Thank you.
吉姆·高登将会跟大家介绍哈维·丹特的真实故事
Jim Gordon can tell you the truth about Harvey Dent.
现在欢迎他上台 高登局长
I'll let him tell you himself. Commissioner Gordon.
真实故事？
The truth?
我准备了一份讲稿
I have written a speech...
是关于哈维·丹特的真实故事
...telling the truth about Harvey Dent.
或许现在不是适当的时机
Maybe the time isn't right.
现在...
Maybe right now...
大家只需要知道
...all you need to know is that there are...
黑门监狱里关了上千名囚犯 这都是归功于丹特法案
...1000 inmates in Blackgate Prison as a direct result of the Dent Act.
他们都是残暴的歹徒 是集团犯罪份子
These are violent criminals, essential cogs in the organized-crime machine.
我只能说 哈维·丹特...
Maybe, for now, all I should say about the death of Harvey Dent is this:
没有白白牺牲
It has not been for nothing.
- 你有看过这家的主人吗？ - 没有 我听说...
- You see the guy who owns the house?  - No. I heard...
- 他从没踏出东宫一步 - 我听说他出了点意外
- ...he never leaves the east wing.  - I heard he had an accident.
- 没错 好像毁容了... - 提尔先生
- Yeah, that he's disfigured. He has to wear a...  - Mr. Till?
你们的人怎么可以使用大厅楼梯？
Why are your people using the main staircase?
波顿太太在哪儿？
And where's Mrs. Bolton?
她在吧台 有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Uh, she's at the bar, sir. Can I help?
你去东宫的房间
The east drawing room.
把门打开 将餐盘放在桌上 然后再把门锁上
Unlock the door, put the tray on the table, lock the door again.
其他什么都别做
Nothing more.
抱歉 泰特小姐 我通报了 但他不想见你
I'm sorry, Miss Tate. I tried, but he won't see you.
你要知道 他并不是针对你
And you mustn't take it personally.
大家都说韦恩先生成天窝在屋里 指甲长到8寸长
Everyone knows that Wayne's holed up in there with 8-inch nails peeing into Mason jars.
真是非常感谢你们让我惨赔
It's very good of you to let me on the grounds.
你何必浪费时间
Why are you wasting your time trying to talk to a man...
他只会把你投入的拯救世界计划丢在一旁
...who threw away your investment on some save-the-world vanity project?
他不能让你的投资回本 但我可以
He can't get your money back. I can.
我可以花时间给你解释拯救世界的企划案 赚不赚钱...
I could try explaining that a save-the-world project, vain or not...
...都是值得投资的 达格先生
...is worth investing in, Mr. Daggett.
像你这种人 眼里只有金钱和权力
But you understand only money and the power you think it buys...
何必来浪费我的时间？
...so why waste my time indeed?
你拿到第二次人事调动报告了？
Second shift reports in?
你应该跟市长混熟一点
You should spend more time with the mayor.
那是你的专长
Well, that's your department.
他看过犯罪统计报告书了吗？
Anyone shown him the crime stats?
他是凭着冲劲在办案的 不管统计数字是多少
He goes by his gut and it bothers him,
他永远不会满意
no matter what the numbers.
那她老婆一定很爱他
Must be popular with his wife.
没有 她带着孩子移居到了克里夫兰
Not really. She took the kids to Cleveland.
他很快就会有时间去探望妻小了
He'll have plenty of time for visits.
市长明年春季要开除他
The mayor's gonna dump him in the spring.
- 真的吗？ - 嗯
- Really?  - Mm-hm.
- 可是他是英雄 - 他是战争英雄 但现在是和平时代
- But he's a hero.  - A war hero. This is peacetime.
对不起 先生 真的很抱歉 韦恩先生
Oh, sorry, sorry. I'm so terribly sorry, Mr. Wayne.
您是韦恩先生 对吧？
It is Mr. Wayne, isn't it?
不过您并没有很长的指甲 也没有满脸疤痕
Although you don't have the long nails or, heh, the facial scars, sir.
大家传说我长那样吗？
Is that what they say about me?
那是因为从来没人见过您
It's just that no one ever sees you.
你的项链真美 让我想起我母亲的项链
That's a beautiful necklace. Reminds me of one that belonged to my mother.
不会是同一条吧...
It can't be the same one...
她的项链一直锁在保险箱里
...because her pearls are in this safe...
厂商说这款保险箱是无法破解的
...the manufacturer clearly explained is uncrackable.
糟糕
Oops.
没人告诉我那保险箱是无法破解的
Nobody told me it was uncrackable.
我恐怕不能让你带走那项链
I'm afraid I can't let you take those.
我想 你不会打女人 而我也不会打残障人士
Look, you wouldn't beat up a woman any more than I would beat up a cripple.
不过 凡事总有例外
Of course, sometimes exceptions have to be made.
晚安 韦恩先生
Good night, Mr. Wayne.
- 我可以搭个便车吗？ - 正合我意
- Can I have a ride?  - You read my mind.
走吧
Let's go.
泰特小姐又来见您
Miss Tate was asking to see you again.
她真固执...
She's very persistent.
而且长得很漂亮 您可能想知道
And quite lovely, in case you were wondering.
- 不想 - 您在做什么？
- I wasn't.  - What are you doing?
我在检查采指纹的粉末 我们家遭小偷了
Examining print dust. We've been robbed.
您不是说要装警铃？
And this is your idea of, uh, sounding the alarm, is it?
她偷走的珍珠项链里面有追踪器
She took the pearls, tracking device and all.
- 谁？ - 一个女仆
- She?  - One of the maids.
你应该禁止她们进出这个房间
Perhaps you should stop letting them in this side of the house.
那您可能要学习自己整理床铺
Perhaps you should start learning to make your own bed.
- 您为什么要采指纹？ - 不是我
- Why were you dusting for prints?  - I wasn't.
是她采的
She was.
长官 基利议员的夫人来电
Sir. Congressman Gilly's wife has been calling in.
她说议员在晚会结束后一直没回家
The congressman never made it home after the Wayne Foundation event.
那是警察的工作？
That's a job for the police?
您和丹特先生的扫黑行动做得太成功
When you and Dent cleaned the streets, you cleaned them good.
我们以后只能去帮图书馆追讨逾期书籍了
Pretty soon we'll be chasing down, uh, overdue library books.
不过 您仍像从前那样坚守岗位
And yet here you are, like we're still at war.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 我叫布莱克 长官
- What's your name, son?  - Blake, sir.
你还有其他问题要问吗？
You have something you want to ask me?
八年前 丹特遇害的那个晚上
It's about that night. This night, eight years ago. The night Dent died.
最后一次看到蝙蝠侠现身
The last confirmed sighting of the Batman.
他杀了人 击退两支特种部队
He murders those people, takes down two SWAT teams...
打断丹特的脖子 然后消失得无影无踪
...breaks Dent's neck and then just vanishes?
我没听懂你的问题
I'm not hearing a question, son.
您不想知道他的真实身份吗？
Don't you want to know who he was?
我很清楚他是谁
I know exactly who he was.
他就是蝙蝠侠
He was the Batman.
我们去找议员夫人吧
Let's go see about the congressman's wife.
韦恩少爷
Master Wayne?
您很久没下来这儿了
You haven't been down here in a long time.
我想查出那个珠宝大盗的底细 我比对了指纹
Trying to find out more about our jewel thief. I ran her prints.
除非她最近减肥成功
Unless she's lost a lot of weight...
否则一定是冒用了别人的指纹
...she was wearing someone else's fingerprints.
她颇有本事
She's good.
或许吧 但我们项链上装有追踪器
She may be, but we have a trace on the necklace.
所以我把她返回的地址
We do. I cross-referenced the address she went back to...
和警方的犯罪数据库相比对
...with police data on high-end B-and-E's, and, um....
找到了瑟琳娜·凯尔
Selina Kyle.
她的数据显示她屡次侥幸脱逃
The databases are full of close-calls, tips from fences.
是有两把刷子 但是她已经快要走投无路了
She's good, but the ground is shrinking beneath her feet.
我们最好赶快通知警方 免得她把项链卖掉
We should send the police before she fences the pearls.
她不会卖 她太喜欢那项链了
She won't. She likes them too much.
而且那不是她原本要偷的东西
And they weren't what she was after.
- 她要偷什么？ - 我的指纹
- What was she after?  - My fingerprints.
她用的是打印机碳粉和石磨的混合粉末
It was printer toner mixed with graphite on the safe.
容易取指纹 又不会被追踪
It gives a good pull and it's untraceable.
太厉害了! 你们两个应该一起喝杯咖啡交换心得
Fascinating. You two should exchange notes over coffee.
你是要把我和珠宝大盗凑成一对吗？
You're trying to set me up with a jewel thief?
为了把你拉回现实世界 我还不惜搓合你和黑猩猩呢!
At this point, I'd set you up with a chimpanzee, if it brought you back to the world.
外面没有什么值得我留恋的
There's nothing out there for me.
这就是问题所在
And that's the problem.
你卸下了披风和面具 但你的人生没有继续下去
You hung up your cape and your cowl but you didn't move on.
你没有认真生活 找个伴侣
You never went to find a life. To find someone.
阿福...
Alfred...
我已经找到了伴侣
...I did find someone.
我知道 但你失去她了
I know, and you lost them.
人生难免会这样
But that's all part of living, sir.
但你没有继续你的人生 你只是空等 期待情势再度恶化
But you're not living, you're just waiting, hoping for things to go bad again.
还记得你离开高谭市的时候吗？
Remember when you left Gotham?
在你成为蝙蝠侠之前
Before all this, before Batman?
你离开了七年
You were gone seven years.
那七年间我一直等 希望你不要回来
Seven years I waited, hoping that you wouldn't come back.
每年我度假的时候 都会去佛罗伦萨
Every year, I took a holiday. I went to Florence.
亚诺河畔的一间咖啡店
There's this cafe on the banks of the Arno.
每天傍晚我都坐在那里 点一杯苦酒
Every fine evening I'd sit there and order a Fernet Branca.
幻想着...
I had this fantasy...
我不经意的一瞥
...that I would look across the tables...
看见你坐在别桌 带着老婆
...and I'd see you there, with a wife.
可能还有几个孩子
Maybe a couple of kids.
你我之间没有任何言语交谈
You wouldn't say anything to me, nor me to you.
但我们都明白 你过得很好 很快乐
But we'd both know that you'd made it. That you were happy.
我从不希望你回来高谭市
I never wanted you to come back to Gotham.
我很清楚这里没有属于你的东西 只有伤痛和苦难
I always knew there was nothing here for you, except pain and tragedy.
我不希望你过这样的日子
And I wanted something more for you than that.
我现在仍这么想
I still do.
我每个月都来这边刷洗好几次
They wash up here a couple of times a month.
天气冷的时候还更频繁
More when it gets colder.
很多游民住在下水道里面
Homeless, sheltering in the tunnels.
我只是把他从下面拉上来 没碰别的
We pulled him from the basin, but other than that we didn't touch him.
- 怎么了？ - 他是吉米
- What?  - Name's Jimmy.
住在圣史文森孤儿院
He's from St. Swithin's.
我球队里的孩子
It's the boys' home where I coach some ball.
吉米好几个月没出现了
Jimmy hadn't been around for months.
- 为什么？ - 布莱克 你应该很清楚
- No? Why?  - Blake, you know why.
他年纪超过16岁了 我们没有经费来负担超过16岁的孩子
He aged out. We don't have the resources to keep boys on after 16.
韦恩基金会不是有提供资金吗？
I thought the Wayne Foundation gave money for that.
最近这几年已经没有了
Not for the past couple of years.
- 他有个弟弟 对吧？ - 叫做马克 我会通知他
- He has a brother here, doesn't he?  - Mark. I'll tell him.
让我来 如果你不介意的话
I'd like to, if that's all right.
你知道你哥哥在下水道里做什么吗？
You know what he was doing in the tunnels?
很多男孩子超过年龄后就会去下水道里面
Lot of guys been going down the tunnels when they age out.
他们说可以住在那里
Say you can live down there.
下面有工作可以做
Say there's work down there.
工作？
Work?
下水道里可以找到什么样的工作？
What kind of work are you gonna find in the sewers?
我想比地面上可以找到的还多吧
More than you can find up here, I guess.
你知道蝙蝠侠？
So you know about him?
当然知道
Of course.
你觉得他会回来吗？
Do you think he's coming back?
不知道
I don't know.
你还带人来约会？
You brought a date?
我喜欢有人帮我开门
I like having someone around to open doors for me.
右手的 不是很完整
Right hand. No partials.
很好
Very nice.
别急 帅哥
Not so fast, handsome.
我要的东西带来没？
You got something for me?
当然有
Ah, yes.
我不知道你要韦恩先生的指纹做什么
I don't know what you're planning to do with Mr. Wayne's prints...
但我猜你应该需要用到拇指
...but I'm guessing you'll need his thumb.
你好像没数清楚啊？
You don't count so good, huh?
我数得很好
I count fine.
事实上 我现在要开始数到十
In fact, I'm counting to 10 right now.
好吧
Okay.
我朋友在外面 只要按发送键就好
My friend's outside. Just hit "send."
这地方好暗
This place is a little dead.
等一下就会很亮 不骗你
It'll liven up in a minute. Trust me.
你还好吧？
Is everything okay?
我很好 待会儿见
Great. Catch you later.
把你答应我的东西交出来
It would have been a lot easier...
就不会弄得这么复杂
...to just give me what we agreed.
我们不想走漏消息
We can't have loose ends.
可惜你打扮得再美 也不会有人记得你
And even in that dress, no one's gonna miss you.
不
No.
你有看到我那个朋友吗？
But my friend over there?
城里所有的警察都在找他
Every cop in the city's missing him.
漂亮
That's cute.
不过警察不会找到这种地方来
But they're not gonna be looking in a place like this.
这很难说 你刚才用了他的手机
I don't know. You did just use his cell phone.
- 快 - 快
- Go!  - Go!
我们是警察 趴下
Police! Get down now!
救命啊! 救命啊!
Help me! Help me!
Help me, please! Please help me!
把伤口压紧 甜心
Keep some pressure on that, sweetheart.
打电话给我？
Call me?
- 小姐 你没事吧？ - 有人流血了! 那边!
- You okay, miss?  - He's bleeding. You gotta help him.
我找到议员了
I got the congressman.
那边!
Clear!
那个入口 打开它 通知水电公司
Manhole! Get this up! Get the DWP down here!
你们三个 跟我一起下去
You three, down with me.
你们两个 去下个出口掩护
You two, you go down, cover the next exit!
高登下去了？
What, they went down there?
- 我们应该要下去看看吧？ - 那是瓦斯气爆 小子
- We're gonna go down there, right?  - That was a gas explosion, kid.
- 瓦斯？这明明是下水道 - 还没弄清楚之前 谁都不准下去
- Wasn't gas. It's a sewer.  - No one goes in till we know what's there.
可是警察局长在下面
We know, sir. The police commissioner.
谁来把这个热血青年带走？
Someone get this hothead out of here?
水电公司的人怎么还不来？
And where's that DWP guy?
你们来这里做什么？
Why are you here?
快回答
Answer him.
我是问你们两个
I was asking you.
他是警察局长
It's the police commissioner.
所以你们把他带下来这里？
And you brought him down here?
- 我们不知道要怎么处理 - 你们惊慌失措
- We didn't know what to do.  - You panicked.
你们的懦弱造成其他三人死亡
And your weakness has cost the lives of three others.
他孤身一人...
No, he's alone.
搜他身
Search him.
然后我再杀了你
Then I will kill you.
- 他死了 - 尸体在哪儿？
- He's dead.  - So show me his body.
不知道流向哪个出水口 我们找不到
The water runs to any one of the outflows. We'd never find him.
- 那就跟踪他 - 跟踪？
- Follow him!  - Follow him?
局长 局长
You okay? You okay?
你还活着吗？
Hey, hey, you awake?
我要见布鲁斯·韦恩
I need to see Bruce Wayne.
很抱歉 韦恩先生不接待未预约的客人
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne doesn't take unscheduled calls.
就算是警察也不例外
Even from a police officer.
如果我去申请搜索票 来调查哈维·丹特的谋杀案
And if I go get a warrant for the investigation of Harvey Dent's murder?
那样也需要预约吗？
That still count as unscheduled?
找我有什么事？
What can I do for you, officer?
高登局长中枪了
Commissioner Gordon's been shot.
他到下水道追缉嫌犯
He chased a gunman down into the sewers.
我救他上来的时候 他含糊地提到一个地下军团
When I pulled him out, he was babbling about an underground army.
有个面罩怪人 名叫贝恩
A masked man called Bane.
你不是应该去向上级报告这件事吗？
Shouldn't you be telling your superior officers?
他们只问他有没有看到巨型的鳄鱼
They asked me if he saw any giant alligators.
他需要你
He needs you.
他需要蝙蝠侠
He needs the Batman.
- 高登局长认为... - 他不知道也不想知道你是谁
- If Commissioner Gordon thinks...  - Oh, he doesn't know or care who you are.
我以前见过你
But we've met before.
很久以前我还是个孩子的时候 在圣史文森孤儿院...
It was a long time ago. I was a kid. Uh, St. Swithin's.
韦恩基金会以前赞助过的孤儿院
It used to be funded by the Wayne Foundation. It's an orphanage.
我妈在我很小的时候出车祸去世了 我对这件事没什么记忆
My mom died when I was small. It was a car accident, I don't really remember it.
几年后我爸被枪杀 因为积欠赌债
But my dad got shot a couple years later over a gambling debt...
这我就记得很清楚
...and I remember that one just fine.
很少人能了解我的感受
Not a lot of people know what it feels like, do they?
那种刻骨铭心的愤怒
To be angry in your bones.
养父母都会说他们可以理解 但那只是很短暂的
I mean, they understand. Foster parents. Everybody understands for a while.
然后他们就开始要求这个愤怒的孩子去做他做不到的事情
And then they want the angry little kid to do something he knows he can't do.
"继续生活下去"
Move on.
所以过一阵子他们就不再体谅
So after a while, they stop understanding.
他们把这个愤怒的孩子送到孤儿院去
They send the angry kid to a boys' home.
我太晚看透这件事 原来我必须学习隐藏愤怒
I figured it out too late. You gotta learn to hide the anger.
对着镜子练习微笑
Practice smiling in a mirror.
就像戴上面具一样
It's like putting on a mask.
有一天 你开着名车 揽着美女出现
So you showed up this one day, in a cool car. Pretty girl on your arm.
我们都很兴奋
We were so excited.
布鲁斯·韦恩 亿万身价的孤儿
Bruce Wayne, billionaire orphan.
我们常常编造关于你的传奇故事...
I mean, we used to make up stories about you, man. Legends.
对别的孩子而言 那只是单纯的故事
And, you know, with the other kids, that's all it was, just stories, but....
但我第一次看到你 就知道你的真实身份
Right when I saw you, I knew who you really were.
我以前就看过你脸上的那种神情
I'd seen that look on your face before.
和我自己练习的表情一样
It's the same one I taught myself.
我不知道你为何要扛下谋杀丹特的罪名
I don't know why you took the fall for Dent's murder...
但我仍然深信蝙蝠侠 就算你不是他
...but I'm still a believer in the Batman even if you're not.
你为什么说韦恩基金会"以前赞助过"你们孤儿院？
Why did you say that your boys' home used to be funded by the Wayne Foundation?
因为赞助金已经终止了
Because the money stopped.
我要去呼吸新鲜空气 开始搜查案情了
Might be time to get some fresh air. Start paying attention to the details.
有些地方可能会需要你的帮助
Some of those details might need your help.
你调查过贝恩那个人了吗？
You check that name? Bane?
他是个雇佣兵 姓名不详
He's a mercenary. No other known names.
他们曾经在西非发动了一场政变
Him and his men were behind a coup in West Africa...
现在帮约翰·达格先生的采矿公司执行保安工作
...that secured mining operations for our friend John Daggett.
- 所以是达格先生把他带来的 - 看来是如此
- Now Daggett's brought them here.  - Or so it seems.
- 我会继续调查 - 好
- I'll keep digging.  - Yeah.
阿福 为什么韦恩基金会终止赞助孤儿院？
Alfred, why did the Wayne Foundation stop funding boys' homes in the city?
基金会的资金来自韦恩企业的利润
The foundation is funded by the profits of Wayne Enterprises.
应该是有的
There have to be some.
- 应该跟福克斯先生聊聊 - 我来打电话
- Time to talk to Mr. Fox, I think.  - I'll get him on the phone.
不用 我们还有车可以用吗？
No, no, no. Do we still have any cars around the place?
还有一两台
Yes. One or two.
帮我预约医院 我想治疗我的腿
I need an appointment at the hospital for my leg.
- 哪间医院？ - 吉姆·高登住的那间
- Which hospital?  - Whichever one Jim Gordon's in.
- 我看过更糟的软骨状况 - 那是好事吗？
- I have seen worse cartilage in knees.  - That's good.
不是 你的膝关节里已经没有软骨
No. That's because there is no cartilage in your knee.
肘关节和肩关节里也所剩不多
And not much of any use in your elbows or your shoulders.
加上肾脏的疤痕组织
Between that and the scar tissue on your kidneys...
脑组织里残留的脑震荡伤害
...the residual concussive damage to your brain tissue...
还有满是伤痕的身体
...and the general scarred-over quality of your body...
- 我真的不建议你从事直升机滑雪 - 我了解了
- I cannot recommend that you go heli-skiing.  - Right.
我们曾经并肩作战
We were in this together...
你却离我们而去
...then you were gone.
人们不再需要蝙蝠侠
The Batman wasn't needed anymore.
- 我们已经胜利了 - 那只是个谎言
- We won.  - Based on a lie.
现在恶势力再度崛起
And now there's evil rising from where we tried to bury it.
蝙蝠侠必须回来
The Batman has to come back.
如果他已经不存在了呢？
What if he doesn't exist anymore?
一定要回来...
He must.
你把我的皮夹偷走了 对吧？
You took my goddamn wallet, didn't you?
- 你把我的皮夹偷走了 - 没有
- You f... You took my wallet!  - No, I...
- 滚出去 - 她偷我的...
- Get out.  - She took my... Ah!
- 快滚 - 变态
- Now.  - Creep!
他干嘛那么生气 里面才60块而已
I don't know what he's so upset about. There's only 60 bucks in here.
还有一支手表
Probably the watch.
- 那位是谁？ - 连爬出跑车都有困难的老头
- Who's that?  - A stiff can barely climb out of his sports car.
- 那是布鲁斯·韦恩 - 韦恩先生 请看这里
- No, that's Bruce Wayne!  - Mr. Wayne, over here!
- 我助理不知有没有... - 这边请 韦恩先生
- I'm not sure if my assistant...  - Right through here.
谢谢
Thank you so much.
布鲁斯·韦恩现身慈善晚会？
Bruce Wayne at a charity ball.
泰特小姐吗？
Miss Tate, isn't it?
您在退隐之前也从未出席过这种场合
Even before you became a recluse, you never came to these things.
其实收入都用来支付举办晚宴的费用
The proceeds go to the big fat spread.
这也说不上是慈善晚会
It's not about charity.
只是用来满足主办人的虚荣而已
It's about feeding the ego of whichever society hag laid this on.
其实这场晚会是我办的 韦恩先生
Actually, this is my party, Mr. Wayne.
晚宴的费用都由我个人负担 收入会全数捐出
And the proceeds will go where they should, because I paid for the big fat spread myself.
您非常慷慨
That's very generous of you.
总得做一些投资才能帮社会解决贫富不均的问题
You have to invest if you want to restore balance to the world.
就像我们的干净能源计划一样
Take our clean-energy project.
有时候投资未必能成功
Sometimes the investment doesn't pay off.
- 我很遗憾 - 你的冷漠是装出来的 韦恩先生
- I'm sorry.  - You have a practiced apathy, Mr. Wayne.
一个对社会漠不关心的人...
But a man who doesn't care about the world...
不可能会投入半数财产来拯救这个世界
doesn't spend half his fortune to save it.
也不会因计划失败而感到如此失落
And isn't so wounded when it fails...
失落到隐世不出
...that he goes into hiding.
祝您有个愉快的夜晚 韦恩先生
Have a good evening, Mr. Wayne.
可以把舞伴借给我吗？
Mind if I cut in?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 你看到我好像不怎么开心 - 你不是应该宅在家里吗？
- You don't seem happy to see me.  - You were supposed to be a shut-in.
我想呼吸点新鲜空气
I felt like some fresh air.
你为什么没报警？
Why didn't you call the police?
我有个厉害的朋友专门处理这类问题
I have a powerful friend who deals with things like this.
你这身服装真亮眼 是扮黑猫女贼吗？
That's a brazen costume for a cat burglar.
是吗？你又是在扮谁？
Yeah? Who are you pretending to be?
布鲁斯·韦恩 亿万身价的怪人
Bruce Wayne, eccentric billionaire.
- 你的男伴是什么人？ - 他老婆在"伊碧莎"岛度假
- Who's your date?  - His wife's in Ibiza.
她把钻石锁在家里 担心被偷走
She left her diamonds behind, though. Worried they might get stolen.
是"艾碧莎"岛才对
It's pronounced "Ibiza."
你不怕被发现你其实是个贼 而不是什么社交名媛吗？
You wouldn't want these folks realizing you're a crook, not a social climber.
你觉得我会在乎那些人是怎么看待我的吗？
You think I care what anyone in this room thinks of me?
我想你根本不在乎任何人对你的看法
I doubt you care what anyone in any room thinks of you.
你不需要附和我 韦恩先生 你对我一无所知
Don't condescend, Mr. Wayne. You don't know a thing about me.
我知道你是瑟琳娜·凯尔 你今天晚上从旧城区过来这里
Well, Selina Kyle, I know you came here from your walk-up in Old Town.
对一个珠宝大盗而言 那住所也未免太寒酸
A modest place for a master jewel thief.
这意味着 你不是在存退休金
Which means that either you're saving for retirement...
就是招惹错人了
...or you're in deep with the wrong people.
你有什么资格评论我？就凭你出生于韦恩豪宅的主卧室吗？
You don't get to judge me because you were born in the master bedroom of Wayne Manor.
- 其实我是在摄政厅出生的 - 刚开始我也是逼不得已
- Actually, I was born in the Regency Room.  - I started out doing what I had to.
这种事一旦开始之后 就回不去了
Once you've done what you had to, they never let you do what you want to.
你可以重新开始
Start fresh.
现今的世界早就没有"重新开始"这种事了
Ugh. There's no fresh start in today's world.
随便一个12岁的小孩都可以用手机查到你的背景
Any 12-year-old with a cell phone could find out what you did.
我们做过的每件事都会被检验 被量化
Everything we do is collated and quantified.
每件事都会被贴上标签
Everything sticks.
所以你就把窃盗行为正当化？
Is that how you justify stealing?
我只会从有钱人的身上偷取我所需要的
I take what I need from those who have more than enough.
我从不偷穷人
I don't stand on the shoulders of people with less.
你以为你是罗宾汉？
Robin Hood?
我相信我做过的善事比在场的每一个人都多 也比你多
I think I'd do more to help someone than most of the people in this room. Than you.
你不觉得你话说得太满？
You think maybe you're assuming a little too much?
或许你才是不切实际 以为你钱包比较大就很屌吗？
Maybe you're being unrealistic about what's really in your pants other than your wallet.
话真呛人
Ouch.
你认为这种好景还能持续多久？
You think all this can last?
一场风暴即将来袭 韦恩先生
There's a storm coming, Mr. Wayne.
你和你的朋友最好准备应战 因为当风暴来袭的时候
You and your friends better batten down the hatches, because when it hits...
你们都将感叹 居然自以为能享尽荣华富贵
...you're all gonna wonder how you ever thought you could live so large...
让我们其余的人受苦受难
...and leave so little for the rest of us.
看来你很期待
You sound like you're looking forward to it.
我很能适应环境
I'm adaptable.
这珍珠项链戴在你身上比放在保险箱里美多了
Those pearls do look better on you than they did in my safe.
不过我还是不能送给你
But I still can't let you keep them.
你把她吓跑了
You... You scared her off!
不会吧
Not likely.
我找不到我的停车券
Must have lost my ticket.
- 您的夫人要您搭出租车回去 - 我夫人？
- Your wife said you were taking a cab home.  - My wife?
只有您一个人吗 少爷？
Just you, sir?
别担心 韦恩少爷
Don't worry, Master Wayne.
重出江湖是需要一点时间的
Takes a little time to get back in the swing of things.
布鲁斯·韦恩 真是稀客啊
Bruce Wayne, as I live and breathe.
你结束冬眠了吗 韦恩先生？
What brings you out of cryo-sleep, Mr. Wayne?
看来你的幽默感一点都没有减
You haven't lost your sense of humor.
不过你却让我损失了很多钱
Even if you have lost most of my money.
事实上 那是你造成的
Actually, you did that.
如果你把所有研发经费都投注在核融合计划
If you funnel your entire R and D budget...
然后又把它整个停掉
...into a fusion project that you then mothball...
这样的公司恐怕很难赚钱
...your company is unlikely to thrive.
有什么解决方案吗？
What are my options?
如果你不愿意启动那台机器...
Well, if you're unwilling to turn on the machine....
我不能那样做 卢修斯
I can't. I can't, Lucius.
那么就只能耐心等候
Well, then sit tight.
你们的多数席次让达格先生无法轻举妄动
Your majority keeps Daggett at bay...
我们可以和米兰达·泰特小姐一起共商能源计划的未来
...while we figure out a future for the energy program with Miranda Tate.
她自始自终都非常支持这个计划
She has supported the project all the way.
她是个聪明人 而且很漂亮
She's smart. And quite lovely.
我们都是为你着想 布鲁斯
We all just want what's best for you, Bruce.
让她看看那台机器
Show her the machine.
我会考虑看看
I'll think it over.
还有其他问题吗？
Anything else?
没了 怎样？
Nope. Why?
通常你来找我都会有一些特殊的需求
These conversations used to end with an unusual request.
我已经退休了
I retired.
既然来了就顺便看样东西吧
Mm-hm. Well, let me show you some stuff anyway.
只是重温旧梦
Just for old times' sake.
我以为这里早就关闭了
I figured you'd have shut this place down.
对外是宣称关闭了
Oh, it was always shut down, officially.
有什么新东西
All this new stuff.
你父亲过世后 韦恩企业成立了14个防御武器子公司
After your father died, Wayne Enterprises set up 14 different defense subsidiaries.
这些年来 我一直在进行合并
For years, I've been shuttering and consolidating...
把所有原型机集合在一起
...all the different prototypes under one roof.
- 就是这里 - 为什么？
- My roof.  - Why?
以免落入有心人士的手中
Keep them from falling into the wrong hands.
你在炫耀就是了
Oh, now you're just showing off.
这是防御部门的专案计划 城市空战和平防御计划
Defense Department projects for tight geometry urban pacification.
它有特殊转子设计 可在水泥丛林里机动飞行 不需要回转
Rotors are configured to maneuver between buildings without recirculation.
这台叫做什么？
What's it called?
公司帮它取了一个又臭又长的名字
Oh, it has a long, uninteresting Wayne Enterprises designation.
我都简称它蝙蝠战机
I just took to calling it the Bat.
依韦恩先生的偏好涂装成黑色
And, yes, Mr. Wayne, it does come in black.
除了自动驾驶以外 其他性能都正常
Works fine, except for the autopilot.
要比我聪明的人才能修好
Takes a better mind than mine to fix it.
比你聪明？
Better mind?
我只是假装谦虚
Well, I was trying to be modest.
你有时间就可以修
A less busy mind.
交给你了
Yours.
- 真的很痛吗？ - 你要不要来试试看 阿福
- Is it really painful?  - You're very welcome to try it, Alfred.
我用看的就好了 谢谢少爷
Happy watching. Thank you, sir.
还不错嘛...
Not bad.
挺不赖的
Not bad at all.
如果你是认真考虑要重操旧业
If you're seriously considering going back out there...
你应该要知道一些贝恩的传闻
...you should hear the rumors surrounding Bane.
说吧
I'm all ears.
在某个古老的国度有一个地牢
There is a prison in a more ancient part of the world.
那是一个地洞 犯人被丢进去折磨到死
A pit where men are thrown to suffer and die.
但有时候 有人能够从黑暗中升起
But sometimes a man rises from the darkness.
有时候 有人能够从地洞中逃出来
Sometimes the pit sends something back.
- 贝恩？ - 没错
- Bane.  - Bane.
他生长于人间地狱
Born and raised in hell on earth.
- 他在地牢里出生的？ - 没人知道他是怎么逃出来的
- Born in a prison?  - No one knows why, or how he escaped.
只知道他逃出来后...
But they do know that once he did...
在你师父忍者大师门下接受训练
...he was trained by Ra's Al Ghul, your mentor.
所以贝恩也是影武者联盟的一员？
Bane was a member of the League of Shadows?
后来他被驱逐出来
And then he was excommunicated.
如果连忍者大师都认为此人太过偏激
And any man who is too extreme for Ra's Al Ghul
那你绝对不能小看他
is not to be trifled with.
我从来就不是个会轻敌的人
I didn't realize I was known for trifling with criminals.
问题就在这里
That was then.
就算你把腿缠起来 戴上面具
And you can strap up your leg and put your mask back on...
也不可能变回从前的你
...but that doesn't make you what you were.
如果这个人真的如你说的那样危险
If this man is everything that you say he is,
那么这个城市需要我
then the city needs me.
这个城市需要的是布鲁斯·韦恩
The city needs Bruce Wayne.
是你拥有的资源和知识
Your resources. Your knowledge.
而不是你的身体 你的生命
It doesn't need your body, or your life.
你的时代已经过去了
That time's past.
你是担心复出之后 我会失败
You're afraid that if I go back out there, I'll fail.
不是
No.
我是担心你想要失败
I'm afraid that you want to.
你不能因为韦恩参加晚会就放空股票
You can't short the stock because Bruce Wayne goes to a party.
韦恩的出现已经引起一些变化 那这变化是好是坏？坏的
Wayne coming back is change. Change is either good or bad. I vote bad.
根据什么判断？
On what basis?
掷铜板决定的
I flipped a coin.
我说不要全麦面包!
It says rye... I said no rye, man.
请脱掉安全帽 让摄影机拍得到你的脸
Hey, rookie, lose the helmet. We need faces for camera.
走吧 我们去倒货
Come on. Let's go scalping.
脱掉吧
Come on.
所有人都趴下
Everybody down, now!
这里是证券交易所 没有钱可以偷的
This is a stock exchange. There's no money you can steal.
是吗？那大家在这里做什么？
Really? Then why are you people here?
所有人都退后 走到街区的尽头
Everybody, stay back! Go down to the end of the block!
我们有紧急情况要处理
We have an emergency situation!
你们快进去
You gotta get in there!
这是人质挟持事件
This is a hostage situation.
不 是抢劫 他们直接进入在线交易网络
No, this is a robbery. They have direct access to the online trading desk.
我不能让我的人冒着生命危险去救你们的钱
I'm not risking my men for your money.
先生 请你移一下车 这里有一些状况发生
We have to ask you to move. We have a situation.
那不是我们的钱 是大家的钱
It's not our money, it's everybody's.
是吗？我的钱都藏在床垫里面
Really? Mine's in my mattress.
如果不及时阻止这些歹徒
You don't put these guys down,
你藏在床垫里的钱很快就会大幅贬值了
that stuffing in your mattress might be worth a whole lot less.
切断光纤线路和移动电话基地台
Cut the fiber cable and take out that cell tower.
- 谢谢 - 这样可以拖延一点时间
- Thank you.  - That'll slow them down.
退后
Move back!
光纤线路被切断了
They cut the fiber.
移动电话网络还可以用
Cell's working.
暂时的
For now.
把路障全给我架起来 这几条街上不许任何人进出
Get all these barriers up. All of them up. No one gets in or out of any of these streets.
我要往那个方向移车？
Where am I supposed to move it?
升起来
Back it up.
你留在车里
All right, just stay in your vehicle, okay?
还需要多少传输时间？
How much longer does the program need?
八分钟
Eight minutes.
该行动了
Time to go mobile.
大家都出去
Everybody, up!
你们两个 过来
You two, move!
谢啦
Thank you.
稳住
Steady.
我看到目标了
I've got something.
不要开枪 有人质
Hold your fire, they've got hostages.
不要开枪
Hold your fire!
行动
Go, go!
放了我
Please! Just let me go!
拜托 放了我
Hey, please! Hey!
打轮胎
Shoot the tires.
打不到
There's no shot.
撤退 撤退 他们有人质
Now back off. Back off, they've got hostages.
四名嫌犯挟持了人质
P.D. are pursuing the four suspects through downtown...
市中心正上演一场警匪追逐
...in response to a hostage situation.
那些灯怎么了？
What's going on with the lights?
不可能呀
It can't be.
那是什么？
What the hell was that?
小子 今晚有好戏看了
Oh, boy, you are in for a show tonight, son.
拜托 救救我
Please! Help, help, help!
对不起
Sorry.
把枪收好 不然倒霉的是你 上车
Put that thing away before you hurt yourself. Get in!
你 快上车 蝙蝠侠出现了
Let's go. You, get in the car. They've spotted the Batman.
把全部的人都叫来
Call everyone in.
所有的巡逻警察 街头警察 还有没值勤的
Every car patrol, beat cop, off-duty too.
通通叫来
Pull them in now.
我现在要做的是吉姆·高登未能完成的壮举
I'm gonna do what Jim Gordon never could.
- 什么壮举？ - 我要抓到蝙蝠侠
- What's that?  - I'm gonna take down the Batman.
四名嫌犯从证券交易所...
are confirming four suspects are carrying two hostages...
...挟持了两名人质
...kidnapped from the Gotham Stock Exchange.
根据目击者表示...
Reports from the eyewitnesses...
- 你看到什么了？ - 我看见蝙蝠侠了
- What do you see?  - I see Batman.
真是令人难以置信 现在又有更多嫌疑犯被人追捕...
Hard to believe, but the suspects are now being pursued...
好像是蝙蝠侠
...by what appears to be the Batman.
好样的
Well, what do you know?
长官 那些持枪歹徒怎么办？
Sir, what about the armed robbers?
拜托 放了我
Please! Just let me go! Please!
一名嫌犯掉头 没有人质 要追吗？
One bike's pulled off. No hostage. Should we pursue?
不要 跟好蝙蝠侠
Negative. Stay on the Batman.
- 他要逃走了 - 你认为应该抓哪一个？
- He's getting away.  - Who do you wanna catch?
无名的抢劫犯？还是杀害哈维·丹特的凶手？
Some robber, or the son of a bitch who killed Harvey Dent?
八年了 他偏偏选在今晚出现
Eight years, and he has to pick tonight.
他把警察从贝恩那边引开了
He's drawing the cops off Bane.
拜托 放了我
Please! Just let me go!
求你了
Please!
(传输完成)
我们跟丢了
We lost him.
怎么可能跟丢？
How could you lose him?
他的火力很强
He's got a lot of firepower.
你们就没有吗？
What, and you don't?
他正在往市中心移动
He's heading back downtown.
我敢说他的脑袋和他的服装一样蠢
Then he's as dumb as he dresses.
包围他
Close it off, gentlemen.
他已成了瓮中之鳖
Like a rat in a trap, gentlemen.
那好像不是鳖 长官
You might have the wrong animal there, sir.
确定是他吗？
You sure it was him?
贝恩说尽管蝙蝠侠出面搅局 任务还是圆满达成了
Bane says the Batman interfered, but the task was accomplished.
被逮捕的手下呢？
What about the men they arrested?
他说"他们死也不会招供"
He said, and I quote, "They would die before talking."
他在哪雇的这么忠诚的人？
Where does he find these guys?
打开香槟
Open the champagne.
我们可以叫一些小姐来吗？
And can we get some girls in here?
小心你的愿望实现啰
Careful what you wish for.
被猫咬到舌头了吗？
Cat got your tongue?
你这个愚蠢的婊子
You dumb bitch.
从来没人说我愚蠢
Nobody ever accused me of being dumb.
你今晚来这里就很愚蠢
You're dumb for coming here tonight.
交出你欠我的东西
I want what you owe me.
门都没有
Want doesn't get.
这身装扮不错 高跟鞋会不会不好走路？
Nice outfit. Those heels make it tough to walk?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说呢？
Do they?
- 在哪里？ - 什么东西？
- So where is it?  - Where's what?
那个"洗底"软件
The program. The "clean slate."
盗贼梦寐以求的终极工具吗？
The ultimate tool for a master thief with a record.
不准动
Hold it right there!
到底在哪里？
Where is it?
"洗底"软件？
The clean slate?
只要在程序里输入一个人的姓名 生日
Where you type in someone's name, date of birth...
几分钟后 就可以把他从全世界的数据库消除？
...in a few minutes they're gone from every database on earth?
- 这么好的东西听起来像真的吗？ - 你骗人
- Sound a little too good to be true?  - You're lying!
铼京公司已经发展到测试阶段
Rykin Data took it to prototype stage.
所以我才买下它
That's why I bought them.
不过他们什么也没有
But they had nothing.
都是虚构的
It was a gangland myth.
退后
Stay back!
我不是说着玩的
I'm not bluffing!
他们知道
They know.
不过他们不在乎
They just don't care.
你开什么玩笑？
You've gotta be kidding me.
- 不准开枪 不准杀人 - 那还有什么乐趣？
- No guns. No killing.  - Where's the fun in that?
我妈说不可以搭陌生人的车
My mother warned me about getting into cars with strange men.
这台不是车
This isn't a car.
再见啰
See you around.
不客气
You're welcome.
情况都在我的掌控之下
I had it under control.
那些人可不是普通的混混
Those weren't street thugs.
都是受过训练的杀手
They were trained killers.
我救了你一命
I saved your life.
告诉我 你把布鲁斯·韦恩的指纹交给谁了
In return, I need to know what you did with Bruce Wayne's fingerprints.
原来韦恩真的有个厉害的朋友
Wayne wasn't kidding about a powerful friend.
我把他的指纹卖给达格先生
I sold his prints to Daggett...
换来的却是一项不存在的东西
...for something that doesn't even exist.
我不相信他能占到你的便宜
I doubt many people get the better of you.
女孩子走投无路的时候...
Hey, when a girl's desperate....
- 他要用来做什么？ - 我不知道
- What's he gonna do with them?  - I don't know...
不过达格十分关注证券交易所的那场抢案
...but Daggett seemed pretty interested in that mess at the stock market.
凯尔小姐
Miss Kyle?
原来是这种感觉
So that's what that feels like.
我看到你上新闻 你又出去搞破坏了吗？
I see from the television coverage that you got your taste for wanton destruction back.
我拿到这个
I retrieved this.
调查证物不是警方的工作吗？
Aren't the police supposed to be investigating, then?
- 他们没有分析工具 - 你把你的工具交给他们就有啦
- They don't have the tools to analyze it.  - They would if you gave them to them.
一个人的工具可能成为另一个人的武器
One man's tool is another man's weapon.
对你这种偏执狂来说 什么都能变成武器
In your mind, perhaps. But there aren't many things you can't turn into a weapon.
阿福 别说了 警方根本做不了事情
Alfred, enough. The police weren't getting it done.
若不是你出来闹场 说不定他们早就抓到凶手了
Perhaps they might have if you hadn't made a sideshow of yourself.
- 你就是认为我做不到 - 你只是让警方把你追得团团转
- You thought I didn't have it in me.  - You led a bloated police force on a chase...
用福克斯给你的新玩具耍耍特技
...with a load of fancy new toys from Fox.
当你只身面对那些暴徒时 你要怎么办？
What about when you come up against him? What then?
我会更奋力搏斗 像从前那样
I'll fight harder. I always have.
你仔细看 他的敏捷 他的残暴 他的训练
Take a look. His speed, his ferocity, his training.
我看见信仰的力量
I see the power of belief.
我看见影武者联盟即将再起
I see the League of Shadows resurgent.
你不是说他被驱逐出门
You said he was excommunicated.
被忍者大师逐出来
By Ra's Al Ghul.
你知道现在的首领是谁？
Who leads them now?
忍者大师是影武者联盟的首领 我已经打败他了
Ra's Al Ghul was the League of Shadows and I beat him.
贝恩只是一介佣兵 我们要查出他究竟想做什么
Bane is a mercenary. We need to find out what he's up to.
看起来像是某种交易 被加密了
Trades of some kind. Coded.
还有我的指纹... 拜瑟琳娜·凯尔之赐
And my fingerprint, courtesy of Selina Kyle.
把这个拿给福克斯
Get this to Fox.
他可以破解密码 查出他们从事什么交易
He can crack the code and tell us what trades they were executing.
我会把这交给福克斯 然后就到此为止
I'll get this to Mr. Fox, but no more.
我把你拉扯大 教你做人的道理 我不愿亲手埋葬你
I've sewn you up, I've set your bones, but I won't bury you.
我已经为韦恩家族送走了太多人
I've buried enough members of the Wayne family.
你要离开我？
You'll leave me?
你总是认为你的人生只有一种结局
You see only one end to your journey.
我只能通过辞职来让你了解
Leaving is all I have to make you understand.
你已不再是蝙蝠侠 你必须寻求其他的生活
You're not Batman anymore. You have to find another way.
你曾说过要退出江湖 去过正常人的生活
You used to talk about finishing, about a life beyond that awful cave.
阿福 瑞秋死了 我们曾许诺要厮守一生
Alfred, Rachel died knowing that we had decided to be together.
正常人的生活已成为过去式 我无法继续我的人生
That was my life beyond the cave. I can't just move on.
她... 她不能...她本来...
She... She didn't. She couldn't.
她怎样？
What if she had?
我不可能改变这一切
She... I can't change that.
假使她死之前曾写一封信告诉你
What if before she died she wrote a letter...
她选择的是哈维·丹特 而不是你？
...saying she chose Harvey Dent over you?
假使为了怕你受伤
And what if to spare you pain...
我把那封信烧掉了呢？
...I burnt that letter?
你竟敢利用瑞秋来企图阻止我？
How dare you use Rachel to try to stop me?
我说的是真的 韦恩少爷
I am using the truth, Master Wayne.
也许我们都不该再继续隐瞒事实 就让真相大白吧
Maybe it's time we all stopped trying to outsmart the truth and let it have its day.
- 我很抱歉 - 抱歉？
- I'm sorry.  - You're sorry?
你以为可以无情地摧毁我的世界
You expect to destroy my world...
然后再跟我握手言和？
...and then think that we're gonna shake hands?
不
No, no, no.
我很清楚会有什么后果
I know what this means.
什么后果？
What does it mean?
后果就是...你会恨我
It means your hatred.
而我也会失去一个人 从他出生的那天起...
And it also means losing someone that I have cared for...
我就一直照料的那个人
...since I first heard his cries echo through this house.
但我也可能因此救了你一条命
But it might also mean saving your life.
那才是我的重点
And that is more important.
再见了 阿福
Goodbye, Alfred.
阿福？
Alfred?
- 你亲自来开门？ - 是啊
- Answering your own door?  - Yeah.
看第三页
Page three.
看来你在期货交易市场上买进了大量的卖权
Seems you made a series of large put options on the futures exchange verified by thumbprint.
那些卖权的履约期限在昨晚到期
Those options expired at midnight last night.
虽然我们最终可证明这是一场诈骗 但现在你已完全破产
Long-term, we may be able to prove fraud. But for now, you're completely broke...
韦恩企业很快就会落入约翰·达格的手中
...and Wayne Enterprises is about to fall into the hands of John Daggett.
那些武器...我们绝不能让达格染指那些武器
The weapons. We can't let Daggett get his hands on Applied Sciences.
那些武器已经被锁起来 而且是帐外资产
Applied Sciences is all locked up and off the books.
但是能源计划就难保了
The energy project, however, is a different story.
米兰达·泰特
Miranda Tate.
我们要说服董事会支持她 带她去看反应器吧
Let's convince the board to get behind her. Let's show her the reactor.
35分钟后和她会面 你赶紧换衣服
We're meeting her there in 35 minutes, so you better get dressed.
你带我来这里就为了看这个 福克斯先生？
You brought me out here to show me this, Mr. Fox?
你要有点耐心 泰特小姐
Bear with me, Miss Tate.
请不要把手脚伸出车厢外
Please keep hands and feet inside the car at all times.
就是这个 对吧？
This is it, isn't it?
反应器放在河流下方
The reactor is beneath the river...
如果有安全缺口的时候 可以轻易用洪水淹没它
...so it can be instantly flooded in the event of a security breach.
布鲁斯·韦恩真的是个偏执狂吗？
Is Bruce Wayne really that paranoid?
我恐怕无法回答这个问题
I'm gonna plead the fifth on that one.
你应该想瞧瞧你所投资的东西
I thought you might like to see what your investment built.
不再使用石化燃料
No fossil fuels.
整个城市都能享用免费的干净能源
Free clean energy for an entire city.
三年前 有位俄罗斯科学家发表一篇论文
Three years ago, a Russian scientist published a paper...
利用核融合反应制作武器
...on weaponized fusion reactions.
一周后 你们就宣称反应器研发遇到瓶颈
One week later, your reactor started developing problems.
我猜这机器运转根本没问题
I think this machine works.
米兰达 如果启动这台机器 高谭市可能会陷入很大的危机
Miranda, if it were operational, the danger to Gotham would be too great.
那位俄罗斯科学家已经在六个月前坠机丧生
Would it make you feel better to know that the Russian scientist...
你可以不用那么担心
...died in a plane crash six months ago?
有心人士一定会研究帕佛博士的论文
Someone will work out what Dr. Pavel did.
然后把这机器改造成核子武器
Someone will figure out a way to make this power source into a nuclear weapon.
我希望你能接手韦恩企业
I need you to take control of Wayne Enterprises...
和这台反应器
...and this reactor.
然后怎么处理？
To do what with it?
什么也不做
Nothing.
直到我们确保它安全无虞
Until we can guarantee its safety.
如果做不到呢？
And if we can't?
用洪水淹了它
Decommission it. Flood it.
摧毁这个世上最佳的永续能源机会？
Destroy the world's best chance for a sustainable future?
如果这世界还没准备好 就这么做
If the world's not ready, yes.
布鲁斯 如果你要拯救这个世界 就要先学会相信它
Bruce, if you want to save the world, you have to start trusting it.
我相信你
I'm trusting you.
那不算数 你是别无选择
Doesn't count. You have no choice.
过去三年来 我随时可以把这里淹掉
I could have flooded this chamber at any time.
现在我选择相信你
I'm choosing to trust you.
拜托你了
Please.
女士们先生们 会议现在开始
All right, ladies and gentlemen. This meeting will now come to order.
我想提醒大家 在座有一位不是我们董事会成员
I'd like to point out that we have a non-board member here...
这不符合议事规则 就算门上挂着他家的姓氏也不行
...which is highly irregular, even if his family name is above the door.
这间公司可是布鲁斯·韦恩的家族一手建立的
Bruce Wayne's family built this company.
而且是他在运营公司
And he himself has run it.
搞得快垮了 你们不同意吗？去看看今天上午的股价
Into the ground, sir! Does anybody disagree? Check the share price this morning.
疯狂式的期货投机行为不但让韦恩先生自己丢掉董事席位
Crazy gambling on futures has not only cost Mr. Wayne his seat...
也害我们所有人都损失惨重
...it's cost us all a lot of money.
他一定要离开
And he has to go.
他说得很有道理 韦恩先生
I'm afraid he has a point, Mr. Wayne.
现在谈公司的事
Now, back to business.
- 韦恩先生 这边 - 变成平民百姓您有什么感受？
- Mr. Wayne, over here!  - How's it feel to be one of the people?
韦恩先生 他们要把你的车拖走 我不知道要怎么办
Mr. Wayne, they're towing your car! I didn't know what to do, they had paperwork.
来搭我的便车吧
Looks like you need a ride, huh?
韦恩先生 您要搭便车吗？
Wayne, we'll give you a ride!
米兰达·泰特为什么会得到韦恩派系的董事支持？
How the hell did Miranda Tate get the inside track on the Wayne board?
她有跟他见面吗？有跟他上床吗？
She been meeting with him? Sleeping with him?
- 据我们所知 没有 - 显然你什么都搞不清楚
- Not that we know of.  - You don't know much of anything, do you?
- 贝恩在哪？ - 我已经跟他说事态紧急
- Where's Bane?  - We told him it was urgent.
- 他到底在... - 说曹操 曹操到
- Where is that masked...  - Speak of the devil and he shall appear.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
- 一切都按照预期计划进行了 - 是吗？
- The plan is proceeding as expected.  - Oh, really?
我现在看起来像是取得韦恩企业的经营权了吗？
Do I look like I'm running Wayne Enterprises right now?
你袭击证券交易所的招数 根本没有奏效
Your hit on the stock exchange, it didn't work, my friend.
你利用我的营造公司在这个城市里24小时不停工作
And now you have my construction crews going around the city at 24 hours a day.
这么做对我吞并韦恩公司的目标有什么帮助？
How exactly is that supposed to help my company absorb Wayne's?
- 你先出去 - 不用 你留下
- Leave us.  - No. You stay here.
我才是这里的老大
I'm in charge.
你真的觉得你是老大？
Do you feel in charge?
我已经付你一笔钱了
I've paid you a small fortune.
你以为这样就可以骑在我头上？
And this gives you power over me?
你想怎样？
What is this?
你的资金和营造团队确实帮了我大忙 但现在已经没用了
Your money and infrastructure have been important till now.
你到底是谁？
What are you?
我是高谭市的末日
I'm Gotham's reckoning.
我来帮大家为这个诅咒画下句点
Here to end the borrowed time you've all been living on.
你才是真正的恶魔
You're pure evil.
这是必要之恶
I'm necessary evil.
不要
No. No, no, no!
你为什么想到要戴面具？
When you started, why the mask?
- 为了保护我身边的人 - 但你不是孤家寡人吗？
- To protect the people closest to me.  - But you were a loner, right?
- 你有家人吗？ - 总有一些我关心的人
- You didn't have any family?  - There are always people you care about.
一直到失去他们后 我才能真正体会
You just don't realize how much until they're gone.
这个构想是要形成一种象征
The idea was to be a symbol.
任何人都可以是蝙蝠侠
Batman could be anybody.
这才是重点
That was the point.
- 我真的很高兴你能回来 - 有些人可不这么想
- Well, it was damn good to see him back.  - Not everybody agrees.
- 他们最后都会想通的 - 你有任何关于贝恩行踪的线索吗？
- They'll figure that out in the end.  - You got anything on Bane's whereabouts?
我有500页的地道资料和一把手电筒
Yeah. I got 500 pages of tunnel records and a flashlight.
欢迎来帮我找
I could use some help, actually.
这样吧 送我去旧城区
You know what? Drop me in Old Town.
我不这么认为
Hey, hey, hey. I don't think so!
- 事情就是这样 - 我不这么认为
- That's the way this works!  - I don't think so!
- 事情就是... - 他不是我们的目标
- That is the way...  - He's not a mark.
而且他现在也没有钱了
And he doesn't have a cent to his name, anyway.
敝舍很寒酸 不过应该比你现在的家好多了
Yeah, it's not much. But it's more than you've got right now.
其实 他们让我继续住那栋房子
Actually, they're letting me keep the house.
原来有钱人破产的方式也跟我们不太一样
The rich don't even go broke the same as the rest of us, huh?
我那个厉害的朋友希望你可以不要离开这里
My powerful friend might hope to change your mind about leaving.
- 他可以给我什么好处？ - 帮你弄到你想要的东西
- And how would he do that?  - By giving you what you want.
- 那东西根本不存在 - 他说有
- It doesn't exist.  - He says it does.
今晚他想跟你见个面
He wants to meet tonight.
为什么？
Why?
他想找贝恩 他说你知道门路
He needs to find Bane. Says you'd know how.
- 跟他说我会考虑的 - 好
- Tell him I'll think about it.  - Okay.
我很喜欢你的公寓
I like your place.
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne?
我很抱歉他们把你的钱全偷走了
I'm sorry they took all your money.
你才不会抱歉呢
No, you're not.
- 有什么事要报告吗？ - 是的
- Can we help you, officer?  - Uh, yeah.
一个钟头前发现约翰·达格的尸体被弃置在垃圾车里面
John Daggett's body was just found in a Dumpster about an hour ago.
- 这个线索可能有点用 - 为什么？
- Thought you might want to know.  - Why?
高谭市大部分地下工程施工许可证上都有他的签名
His name's all over these permits I just pulled to, uh, map the tunnels under Gotham.
包括地铁隧道、地下管线、下水道工程等等
That's MTA maintenance, uh, sewer construction, couple of other things.
你为什么没调查地下通道？
Where did you get to with the tunnel searches?
你这热血青年是来提醒我的吗？
Remind me to tell detail to keep hotheads out.
我们派了几个小组下去 那是个巨大的地下网络
We've had teams down there. It's a huge network.
加派一些人手 一处都不能漏掉 要抓到他
Well, get more men. Work a grid. I want him found.
是的 面罩怪人 我们已经在搜查了
Yeah, the, uh, masked man. We're on it.
不要再穿这身制服了 现在开始你在我下面做事
Lose the uniform, you're working for me now.
我们需要很多热血青年
We could use some hotter heads around here.
- 达格的死亡也有可能是巧合 - 你现在的身份是警探
- Sir, that could also be a coincidence.  - You're a detective now, son.
不能再相信世上有巧合这种事了
You're not allowed to believe in coincidence anymore.
没人帮你开门吗？
Nobody's answering.
没有...
No.
现在只剩我一个人了
I'm on my own now.
你有钥匙吧？
Do you have keys?
从来没用过那种东西
Never needed them.
希望你不是因为钱才喜欢我的
Hope you didn't like me for my money.
困顿的环境可以升华你的人格
Suffering builds character.
我会好好照顾你父母的遗物 布鲁斯
I'll take care of your parents' legacy, Bruce.
她是谁？
Who's this?
阿福去哪了？
Where's Alfred?
他走了
He left...
把一切都带走了
...taking everything.
发生什么事了？
What's that?
被断电了
My power's been shut off.
你很会升火
You're good at that.
小时候 我们一贫如洗
When I was a child, we had almost nothing.
夜里升起火 就会感觉内心非常富足
But on the nights when we had a fire, we felt very rich indeed.
我还以为你来自富裕的家庭
I assumed your family was wealthy.
不是一开始就有钱 小时候很穷
Not always. Not when I was young.
只是一段往事
An old mistake.
我也有一些往事
I've made a few myself.
真不少呢
More than a few.
我们可以离开这里
We could leave.
今天晚上
Tonight.
搭我的飞机 到任何我们想去的地方
Take my plane, go anywhere we wanted.
改天吧
Someday, perhaps.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
别害羞
Don't be shy.
韦恩说你可以弄到"洗底"软件
Wayne says you can get me the clean slate.
- 那要看情况 - 什么情况？
- That depends.  - On what?
看你的用途
On what you want it for.
我买下它是为了避免落入坏人手中
I acquired it to keep it out of the wrong hands.
你好像不信任我嘛
Still don't trust me, huh?
怎样才能让你相信我？
How can we change that?
先带我去见贝恩
Start by taking me to Bane.
是你自找的
You asked.
从这里开始就会有贝恩的人巡逻
From here, Bane's men patrol the tunnels.
他们不是普通的混混
And they're not your average brawlers.
我也不是
Neither am l.
- 他在你后面 - 谁？
- He's behind you.  - Who?
我
Me.
你在做...
What do you think you're...
快到了
Just a little further.
我总得想个办法保护我自己的性命
I had to find a way to stop them trying to kill me.
你铸下大错了
You made a serious mistake.
我想你铸下的错恐怕更严重
Not as serious as yours, I fear.
贝恩
Bane.
我们就不必客套了
Let's not stand on ceremony here...
韦恩先生
...Mr. Wayne.
和平会消磨你的力量
Peace has cost you your strength.
胜利会挫败你的意志
Victory has defeated you.
你这障眼法只能用来对付未受训练的人
Theatricality and deception, powerful agents to the uninitiated.
我们都受过训练 不是吗 布鲁斯？
But we are initiated, aren't we, Bruce?
同出身于影武者联盟
Members of the League of Shadows.
你背叛了我们
And you betrayed us.
没错 而你被一群丧心病狂驱逐出来
"Us"? You were excommunicated by a gang of psychopaths.
我就是影武者联盟
I am the League of Shadows.
我是来完成忍者大师的遗志
And I'm here to fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny.
你像年轻人般地奋战
You fight like a younger man.
毫无保留
Nothing held back.
令人钦佩 但你错估了形势
Admirable, but mistaken.
你以为黑暗是你的盟友？
Oh, you think darkness is your ally?
但你只是利用了黑暗
But you merely adopted the dark.
我则是生于黑暗之中
I was born in it.
长于黑暗之中
Molded by it.
直到我长大成人才首次见到光明
I didn't see the light until I was already a man.
在那之前只有无尽的黑夜
By then, it was nothing to me but blinding!
黑暗出卖了你 因为我才是黑暗的支配者
The shadows betray you because they belong to me!
我会带你去看我的家乡
I will show you where I have made my home...
在此同时 我们将准备让正义得到伸张
...whilst preparing to bring justice.
然后 再把你粉碎
Then I will break you.
对于你提供的珍贵武器 深表谢意 正合所需
Your precious armory. Gratefully accepted. We will need it.
对嘛 我还在想说要先粉碎哪一个
Ah, yes. I was wondering what would break first.
你的意志...
Your spirit...
还是你的身体？
...or your body.
帮我接高登局长 议员绑架案有线索了
Get me Commissioner Gordon. I got a line on the congressman's kidnapping.
- 打扰一下 小姐 - 有事吗？
- Excuse me, miss.  - Uh, yes?
可以让我看一下你的机票和身份证件吗？
I'm gonna need to see your ticket and identification, please.
好 帮我拿一下
Oh. Do you mind?
我把你的照片拿给议员看 你猜怎么着
I showed your picture to the congressman. Guess what.
别说了 他还爱着我？
Don't tell me. Still in love?
爱得死去活来 他提起告诉了
Oh, head over heels. Pressing charges, though.
你有过不少前科 凯尔小姐
You've made some mistakes, Ms. Kyle.
- 只是混口饭吃 - 你胃口很大嘛
- Girl's gotta eat.  - And you have an appetite.
你为什么要逃走？前科累累 想躲过警察也很难
Why would you run? You can't hide with a record like this.
我不是在躲警察
Maybe it's not you I'm running from.
那是躲谁？贝恩吗？
Who then? Bane?
你知道他哪些事？
What do you know about him?
你应该和我一样怕他
That you should be as afraid of him as I am.
我们可以提供庇护
We can offer you protection.
好吧
Okay.
我是因为在找一个朋友才盯上你的 布鲁斯·韦恩
When I spotted you, I was looking for a friend of mine. Bruce Wayne.
他们把他杀了吗？
Did they kill him?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
你为何不干脆杀了我？
Why didn't you just kill me?
那样太便宜你了
You don't fear death, you welcome it.
你必须接受更严厉的惩罚
Your punishment must be more severe.
折磨我？
Torture?
没错
Yes.
但不是你的身体
But not of your body.
而是你的灵魂
Of your soul.
这是哪里？
Where am l?
家乡
Home.
在这里我学到了什么是真正的绝望
Where I learned the truth about despair.
很快你也会学到
As will you.
这个地牢是最可怕的人间地狱
There is a reason why this prison is the worst hell on earth:
因为有"希望"
Hope.
数千年来 这里的囚犯无不抬头仰望那道光明
Every man who has rotted here over the centuries...
幻想着爬出地牢重获自由
...has looked up to the light and imagined climbing to freedom.
就是这么容易 这么单纯
So easy. So simple.
如同大海里的船难漂流者 饮海水止渴
And like shipwrecked men turning to seawater from uncontrollable thirst...
很多人都因此摔死了
...many have died trying.
就是因为存在希望 才有真正的绝望
I learned here there can be no true despair without hope.
所以当我的恐怖笼罩高谭市时
So as I terrorize Gotham...
我会利用这点来折磨他们的灵魂
...I will feed its people hope to poison their souls.
让他们以为还有一丝生存的希望
I will let them believe that they can survive...
然后看着他们踩着彼此的身体争相爬向阳光
...so that you can watch them clambering over each other to stay in the sun.
你将会眼睁睁地看我们折磨这座城市
You can watch me torture an entire city.
到时候你就会明白自己有多失败
And then when you have truly understood the depth of your failure...
我们一定会完成忍者大师的遗愿
...we will fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny.
我们会摧毁高谭市
We will destroy Gotham.
当使命完成
And then, when it is done...
高谭市化成灰烬时
...and Gotham is ashes...
你就可以领死了
...then you have my permission to die.
她要被关在这里？
You're locking her up in here?
根据丹特法案 特殊情况可以不需要隔离
The Dent Act allows non-segregation based on extraordinary need.
她16岁就从女子感化监狱逃出来
First time she broke out of women's correctional, she was 16.
宝贝 靠过来一点
Little closer, baby.
想牵牵我的小手吗？
Why, honey? You wanna hold my hand?
她不会有什么问题的
She's gonna be fine.
为何董事会要开会讨论能源计划？
I still don't see the need of a board meeting for the energy project.
布鲁斯做了很多正确的决策
Bruce got a lot of things right.
但是不应该瞒着董事会
Keeping the board in the dark was not one of them.
欢迎你们加入
How good of you to join us.
主席 董事长
Chair. President.
现在我还需要一名董事会成员
All I need now is one more ordinary board member.
福克斯先生 不如你帮我选一位吧？
Mr. Fox, would you like to nominate?
不用了 我自愿
No. I will volunteer.
你要把我们带去哪里？
Where are you taking us?
你说对了 局长 可以让我们说个话吗？
You were right, commissioner. Will you excuse us, please?
发生什么事了？
What happened?
面罩怪人绑架了韦恩企业董事会
Your masked man kidnapped the Wayne Enterprises board.
大部分的成员都释放了 不过他把三个人带进了下水道
He let most of them go, but he took three into the sewers.
不要巡逻了 不能再玩捉迷藏
No more patrols. No more hide and seek.
把所有能调动的警力都派下去 把他们揪出来
Get every available cop down there and smoke him out!
市长不希望引起恐慌
The mayor won't want panic.
那就对外说是演习？
So it's a training exercise.
很抱歉我先前没把你当一回事
I'm sorry I didn't take you seriously.
你不用去
Not you.
你要负责向我报告蝙蝠侠的行踪
You're telling me the Batman's gone...
所以你去追查达格的那条线 要不择手段
...so you chase up the Daggett leads any way you can.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
他问你愿意付多少钱求我们让你死
He asks how much you would pay us to let you die.
我跟他说你一贫如洗
I told him. I told him you have nothing.
就请他当作是消遣让我一死吧
Do it for the pleasure.
他付我们一笔钱让你维持生命
They pay me more than that to keep you alive.
那个人要尝试爬出去
He will try the climb.
有人成功过吗？
Has anyone ever made it?
当然没有
Of course not.
他说有一个人成功过
He says there is one who did.
一个孩子
A child.
在这个地狱里出生的孩子
A child born in this hell.
贝恩
Bane.
只是个传说罢了
An old legend. Nothing more.
不要
Don't.
他们要你亲眼目睹的惨剧 就快要开始了
Whatever it is they want you to see, it's happening soon.
引爆
Fire in the hole!
启动它
Turn it on.
我只需要再抓一个董事过来就好 还有八个人在等着呢
I only need one other board member. There are eight others waiting.
恕难从命
I won't do it.
好吧 住手
All right, stop.
卢修斯 你会害死这个人和你自己
Lucius, you'll kill this man, and yourself...
那么做也拖延不了多少时间
...and you'll barely slow them down.
去吧 做你的工作
Go on, then. Do your work.
把它展现给世人
Take them up to the surface.
人民有权体验...
People of their status...
西方文明的新世代
...deserve to experience the next era of western civilization.
我调查到达格的水泥工厂向多个地点的地下管道灌注了水泥
I've been to half of Daggett's cement plants and locations they poured underground.
灌入的东西有没有可疑之处？
Anything strange about the pourings?
坦白说 局长 我对土木工程一窍不通
Honestly, commissioner, I don't know anything about civil engineering.
但是你熟悉行为模式 继续调查
But you know about patterns. Keep looking.
完成了
It's done.
现在这是一颗四百万吨的核子弹
This is now a 4-megaton nuclear bomb.
把核心从反应器卸下来
Pull the core out of the reactor.
不 不可以这么做
No, you cannot.
那是唯一能够维持它稳定的能源
This is the only power source capable of sustaining it.
如果你卸下来 几个月后核心就会劣化
If you move it, the core will decay in a matter of months.
五个月 根据我推算
Five, by my calculations.
那样会爆炸的
And then it will go off!
为了你的孩子着想 帕佛博士
And for the sake of your children, Dr. Pavel...
它最好要给我爆炸
...indeed I hope it does.
嘿
Hey. Hey!
我在证券交易所门口见过你 对吧？
That was you in front of the stock exchange, wasn't it?
- 什么时候？ - 什么时候？
- When?  - When?
警察要封锁街道的时候 你的卡车挡到了路
When cops were trying to pull onto Castle Street and your truck was shutting them out.
- 没错 你就是那个警察 - 现在是警探了
- Oh, yeah. You're the cop.  - Detective now.
身为警探 我不相信这世上有所谓的巧合
And, uh, as a detective, we're not allowed to believe in coincidence.
你怎么会在这里？你们要做什么？
What were you doing here? What are you working on?
局长 我是布莱克
Commissioner, it's Blake.
我找到两个死亡的目击者 留下一堆疑问 请回电...
I got two dead witnesses and a lot of questions. Call me whenev...
等等 我看到四桶聚异丁烯
Wait a minute. I'm looking at four barrels of polyisobutylene.
他们不是在制作水泥
That looks like motor oil right next to it.
而是做炸药
Jesus, they're not making cement. They're making explosives.
- 帮我转接佛利 - 佛利正在执行任务
- Patch me in to Foley.  - Foley's overseeing the operation.
他们进去的地道是陷阱
They're heading into a trap!
我们看到数千名警力进入下水道
We're seeing thousands of police heading into the sewers.
- 请问市长 数以千计的警力... - 这只是演习活动
- Mr. Mayor? Literally thousands.  - It's a training exercise, that's all.
若不介意 我现在要进去看本市的球队痛宰对手
Now if you'll excuse me, I've got tickets to watch our boys thrash Rapid City.
- 我是佛利 - 那是陷阱 快叫大家出来
- Foley.  - It's a trap! Pull everyone out!
- 贝恩把炸药混入水泥灌进地底下 - 在哪里？
- Bane has been pouring concrete laced with explosives!  - Where?
∮ 哦 你能在黎明的晨光中看到吗 ∮
∮ Oh, say, can you see By the dawn's early light ∮
∮ 我们在暮色中如此骄傲地欢呼 ∮
∮ What so proudly we hailed At the twilight's... ∮
地下通道周围一整圈 他们计划要把警方困在地底下
There's a ring around the tunnels! They'll blow it and trap the cops underground!
快撤退 把大家撤出来 快
Pull them out. Pull them out now!
∮ 在危险的战斗中 ∮
∮ Through the perilous fight ∮
∮ 我们看到的城墙 ∮
∮ O'er the ramparts we watched ∮
∮ 是如此的殷勤 ∮
∮ Were so gallantly streaming ∮
∮ 火箭的红光 ∮
∮ And the rockets' red glare ∮
∮ 炸弹在空中爆炸 ∮
∮ The bombs bursting in air ∮
多么动人的歌声啊
That's a lovely, lovely voice.
∮ 我们的旗帜还在那里 ∮
∮ ...that our flag was still there ∮
∮ 哦 那星条旗还在飘扬吗 ∮
∮ Oh, say does that star-spangled banner Yet wave ∮
∮ 自由之地 ∮
∮ O'er the land of the free ∮
∮ 勇敢者的家 ∮
∮ And the home of the brave ∮
游戏开始了
Let the games begin.
大家都没事吧？
Everybody okay?
- 我们行动吧 - 快 快
- Let's move! Move, move!  - Go, go!
高谭市的市民
Gotham...
现在起接管...
...take control.
接管你们的城市
Take control of your city.
- 佛利 - 我的天啊 布莱克
- Foley.  - Jesus, Blake.
全部的警力都困在地底下了
Every cop in the city's in those tunnels.
不是全部
Not every cop.
先生 你没事吧？我是警察 我现在需要用你的车
Sir, are you okay? I'm a police officer. I need your car right now.
你忘了检查角落 菜鸟
Clear the corners, rookie.
帮我拿外套 小子
Get my coat, son.
这台就是解放你们的机器
This....This is the instrument of your liberation.
卫星侦测到放射波段
Satellite shows a radiation spike.
总之 那是个核子武器
Whatever it is, it's nuclear.
向大家自我介绍
ldentify yourself to the world.
我是蓝尼·帕佛 核物理学家
Dr. Leonid Pavel, nuclear physicist.
帕佛被证实死于空难
Pavel was confirmed dead.
从乌兹别克撤离的途中 但...
Plane crash on an agency pull out of Uzbekistan, but....
看起来是他没错
It looks like it's him.
告诉大家这是什么？
And what... What is this?
这是一个完全启动的中子炸弹
It's a fully primed neutron bomb...
爆炸半径6英里
...with a blast radius of six miles.
谁能够解除这个装置？
And who is capable of disarming such a device?
只有我一人
Only me.
只有你一人
Only you.
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, good doctor!
听好了 这个炸弹已经启动
Now, this bomb is armed!
这个炸弹会到处移动
And this bomb is mobile!
没有人知道引爆者的身份
And the identity of the triggerman is a mystery.
因为引爆器握在你们其中一人的手里
For one of you holds the detonator!
他不是要征服这个城市
Now, we come here not as conquerors...
而是要解放这个城市 把这个城市主控权交还给市民
...but as liberators, to return control of this city to the people.
一旦发现外界伸出援手
And at the first sign of interference from the outside world...
或是有人企图逃跑
...or from those people attempting to flee...
这位无名的高谭市民
...this anonymous Gothamite...
这位不被歌颂的英雄就会引爆炸弹
...this unsung hero, will trigger the bomb.
现在起实施戒严
For now, martial law is in effect.
各位先回家 拥抱你的家人
Return to your homes, hold your families close...
静静等待
...and wait.
明天起你们就要争取自己应得的权利
Tomorrow, you claim what is rightfully yours.
暂时按兵不动
Pull back the fighters.
先派出高空侦察机
Start high-level reconnaissance flights.
帮我联络总统
Get the president on the line.
坦克和飞机都无法阻止我们引爆炸弹
Tanks and planes cannot stop us from detonating our device.
派一名代表过来谈判补给和通讯的条件
Send an emissary to discuss terms of access for supplies and communication.
你们有多少人？
How many of you are there, son?
以你们的人数不可能阻止1200万人离开这个岛
You don't have enough men to stop 12 million people from leaving this island.
没错 我们没办法
No. No, we don't.
但你们可以
But you do.
我怎么可能帮你们看守人质？
Now, why the hell would I try to help you keep your hostages?
只要有一个人走过这座桥
If one person crosses this bridge...
高谭市就会整个爆炸
...Gotham gets blown to hell.
高谭市民拥有坚强的意志
The people of our greatest city are resilient.
他们过去曾展露无遗 未来也不会令大家失望
They have proven this before, and they will prove it again.
我们绝不和恐怖份子妥协
We do not negotiate with terrorists...
但我们必须认清现实
...but we do recognize realities.
无论情势如何发展
As this situation develops...
有件事请大家一定要明白
...one thing must be understood above all others.
我们绝对不会遗弃高谭市民
People of Gotham, we have not abandoned you.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思就是我们现在孤立无援了
It means we're on our own.
我应该要发表公开演说
I have to get in front of a camera.
长官 你一露脸 他们就会马上杀了你
They will kill you the second you show your face.
贝恩说他要把高谭市还给市民 我要让大家知道我能领导他们
Bane says he's giving Gotham back to the people. They need to know I could lead.
贝恩不可能让你这么做
Bane's not gonna let that happen.
那就让他露出真面目
Then he'll show his true colors.
你自己也会送命
And you'll be dead.
你们后方矗立的 就是高谭市受压迫的象征
Behind you stands a symbol of oppression.
黑门监狱
Blackgate Prison...
这监狱里有上千人因为某个人而受尽折磨
...where a thousand men have languished under the name of this man:
那就是哈维·丹特
Harvey Dent.
他一直被塑造成正义的化身
Who has been held up to you as the shining example of justice!
在你发表电视演说前 我们必须协助你藏身
We're just gonna keep moving you till we can get you in front of the camera.
一直以来你们都拜错了偶像
You have been supplied with a false idol to stop you...
才让这个城市继续腐败下去
...tearing down this corrupt city!
今天我向大家揭发哈维·丹特的真面目
Let me tell you the truth about Harvey Dent.
以下是引述自高谭市警察局长吉姆·高登的讲稿
From the words of Gotham's police commissioner James Gordon:
"蝙蝠侠并没有杀害哈维·丹特"
"The Batman didn't murder Harvey Dent.
"他救了我儿子一命"
He saved my boy...
"还替哈维所犯下的骇人罪行扛起责任"
...then took the blame for Harvey's appalling crimes...
"好让我能够厚颜无耻地"
...so that I could, to my shame...
"为这位堕落的偶像编造谎言"
...build a lie around this fallen idol.
"过去我每年都歌颂这个试图杀害我儿子的狂人"
I praised the madman who tried to murder my own child.
"如今我已无法继续忍受自己的谎言"
Well, I can no longer live with my lie.
"现在我将这个事实公诸于世"
It is time to trust the people of Gotham with the truth...
"同时辞去我的职务"
...and it is time for me to resign."
你们愿意接受这位仁兄的辞呈吗？
And do you accept this man's resignation?
你们愿意让那些骗子 那些腐败的官员
And do you accept the resignation of all of these liars?
全部辞职下台吗？
Of all the corrupt?
八年来那么多人被关进黑门监狱
Those men locked up for eight years in Blackgate...
因为丹特法案而不得假释 全都建立在一个谎言上？
...and denied parole under the Dent Act, it was based on a lie.
当时的高谭市需要一个英雄
Gotham needed a hero.
高谭市现在更需要英雄 你背叛了你所捍卫的价值
Well, it needs it now more than ever, but you betrayed everything you stood for.
当一个体制完全背离了人们的信任
There's a point far out there when the structures fail you...
法律不但无用武之地
...when the rules aren't weapons anymore...
反而成为枷锁 让坏人为所欲为
...they're shackles, letting the bad guy get ahead.
有一天 你可能也会面临这样的困境
One day, you may face such a moment of crisis.
到时候 我希望你也有个像蝙蝠侠那样的朋友
And in that moment, I hope you have a friend like I did...
能自愿背黑锅 好让你继续当个不沾锅
...to plunge their hands into the filth, so that you can keep yours clean!
在我看来你很黑 局长
Your hands look plenty filthy to me, commissioner.
我们拯救高谭市 免于受腐败官吏的摧残
We take Gotham from the corrupt!
富人的摧残
The rich!
这些人编造机会的神话
The oppressors of generations...
世世代代压迫着你们小老百姓
...who have kept you down with myths of opportunity.
现在我们把高谭市归还给你们...
And we give it back to you...
全体市民
...the people.
高谭市就在你们手里
Gotham is yours!
无人能够干预 尽情地享受吧
None shall interfere. Do as you please.
就从推倒黑门监狱开始 释放人犯
But start by storming Blackgate and freeing the oppressed!
开门
Open it!
向前迈进吧 受刑人
Step forward, those who would serve...
你们将组成一支军队
...for an army will be raised.
把特权人士从他们的安乐窝里拖出来
The powerful will be ripped from their decadent nests...
丢进冷酷世界里
...and cast out into the cold world that we know and endure!
他们将接受法院审判
Courts will be convened.
尽情蹂躏他们
Spoils will be enjoyed.
让他们血流成河
Blood will be shed!
警察可以留下
The police will survive...
但他们必须先学会维持真正的正义
...as they learn to serve true justice.
这个伟大的城市
This great city...
必须咬紧牙关
...it will endure.
高谭市才能更长久
Gotham will survive!
他说你得先治好你的背
He says you must first fix your back.
他怎么知道？
How does he know?
他以前是个狱医
He was the prison doctor.
染上了吗啡毒瘾 不过他在这里救治了很多人
He's a morphine addict who incurred the displeasure...
包括你那戴面罩的朋友
...of powerful people, including your masked friend.
怎么一回事？
How?
很久以前 那个瘟疫的年代
Many years ago, it was a time of plague.
有一群囚犯攻击贝恩
Some of the other prisoners attacked Bane.
这位医生尽力帮他治疗伤口
The doctor's fumbling attempts to repair the damage...
但还是留下了永久的疼痛
...left him in perpetual agony.
于是他用面罩来帮他止痛
The mask holds the pain at bay.
贝恩就是那个逃出去的孩子？
Bane was the child you spoke of?
他在这里出生的？
He was born here?
传说有一个佣兵 他效力于一个本地军阀
The legend is that there was a mercenary who worked for a local warlord.
他爱上了军阀的女儿
He fell in love with the warlord's daughter.
他们秘密结婚
They were married in secret.
但后来被军阀发现
When the warlord found out...
那个佣兵被关进这个地牢
...the mercenary was condemned to this pit.
但后来又被流放
But then he exiled him instead.
他大概猜想是军阀的女儿帮他求情
The mercenary understood that it was the daughter who had secured his release.
但是他不知道自由背后的真正代价
But what he could not know was the true price of his freedom.
她代替他关进这座地牢
She took his place in the pit.
当时还怀着孩子
And she was with child...
那佣兵的孩子
...the mercenary's child.
阴暗的地底是不可能绽放出纯真的花朵
Innocence cannot flower underground. It has to be stamped out.
有一天医生忘了帮她锁上牢房
One day, the doctor forgot to lock the cell.
幸好那个孩子有个朋友
But the child had a friend...
他的守护者 他极力保护那纯真的孩子
...a protector who showed the others that this innocence was their redemption.
孩子的母亲就没那么幸运了
It was to be prized. The mother was not so lucky.
现在这里是贝恩的监狱 不能再讲下去了
This is Bane's prison now. He wouldn't want this story told.
你背上有一节脊椎突出
There's a vertebra protruding from your back.
要把它弄回去才行
It has to be put back.
维持这个姿势 直到你站起来
Stay like this until you stand.
没想过我会回来吧 布鲁斯？
Tsk, tsk, tsk. Did you not think I would return, Bruce? Hmm?
我说过我是永生的
I told you I was immortal.
我亲眼...亲眼看到你死的
I watched... I watched you die.
永生的形式有很多种
Oh, there are many forms of immortality.
我曾经有一个妻子
Once, I had a wife...
我的挚爱
...my great love.
- 她被人从我身边带走了 - 你就是那个佣兵
- She was taken from me.  - You were the mercenary.
贝恩是你的孩子
Bane is your child.
你的继承人
Your heir.
我们影武者联盟是来恢复文明平衡的
An heir to ensure the League of Shadows fulfills its duty to restore balance to civilization.
不
No.
这么多年来 你对抗高谭市的邪恶势力
You yourself fought the decadence of Gotham for years...
耗尽你的意志...
...with all your strength...
你的资源 你的信念
...all your resources, all your moral authority.
而你仅存的胜利却是一个谎言
And the only victory you could achieve was a lie.
现在你明白了吧？高谭市已无可救药
Now you understand. Gotham is beyond saving.
不
No.
- 这个城市必须毁灭 - 不
- And must be allowed to die.  - No!
抬起你的头
Yeah, just lift your head.
很好
Oh, that's good.
不要扶我
No, no!
- 那是什么？ - 某个人的家
- What's that?  - This was someone's home.
现在这里是属于每一个人的
And now it's everyone's home.
风暴来袭 对吧？这是我们梦寐以求的
There's a storm coming, remember? This is what you wanted.
这是给巴士用的 说不定哪天有幸能够撤离
It's for the bus, in case there's a chance to evacuate.
有局长的消息吗？
Any news? Is the commissioner...
不要知道比较好 孩子们还好吗？
The less you know, Father. How are the boys doing?
现在电力比较充足 有时还可以看电视
Well, we've had more power on, so they've got some TV.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
布莱克 小心点 警察现在都成了落水狗
Blake, you be careful out there. They're hunting down cops like dogs.
干嘛要锻炼身体？
Why build yourself?
- 我不想死在这里面 - 反正终究难逃一死 有什么差别？
- I'm not meant to die in here.  - Here, there. What's the difference?
我说过那是不可能的事
I told you it could not be done.
你说有个孩子成功逃出去过？
You told me a child did it.
那不是普通的孩子
But no ordinary child.
而是生于地狱的孩子
A child born in hell.
在苦难中成长
Forged from suffering.
在悲痛里茁壮
Hardened by pain.
不是像你这种来自优越环境的人
Not a man from privilege.
已经暗中派人过去了
We got boots on the ground, sir.
现在就等消息
Just waiting on intel.
你有证件吗？
You have ID?
当然没有
Of course not.
- 那我们要如何相信你？ - 我们别无选择了
- Well, how can we trust you?  - We don't have any choice.
高登局长 我是特种部队的琼丝上尉
Commissioner Gordon. Captain Jones, Special Forces.
很高兴你们前来支援
Captain. Glad to have you here.
这是我们的职责 你们有多少警力？
It's our job, sir. Now, uh, how many of you are there?
几十人 没有仔细算
Well, there's dozens. I'd rather not say exactly.
但是困在地底下的有将近三千人
But the men trapped underground number almost 3000.
- 他们目前情况如何？ - 有送食物和水进去
- Condition?  - Getting food and water.
- 有办法把他们救出来吗？ - 可以 长官
- Can we break them out?  - Yes, sir.
只要解决掉公园南端出水口的卫兵
Take out the mercenaries south of Ackerman Park.
就可以炸开一个供10人通行的大洞
Blow the rubble, make a hole big enough for 10 at a time.
我一直和地底下的同事保持联系 他们已经准备周全
I'm in contact with my partner who's down there. They're just waiting.
他们都三个月没见过阳光了
Men who haven't seen daylight in three months?
三个月没见过阳光 但仍是警察
Officers who haven't seen daylight in three months.
炸弹要怎么办？卫星侦测不到辐射点
What about the bomb? Satellite can't pick up radiation hot spots.
他们把炸弹放在卡车内
They keep it on a truck.
一定是用内衬铅线的屋顶遮蔽起来了
It must have a lead-lined roof.
那辆卡车持续地移动
They move it constantly.
很好 所以你们知道是哪一辆卡车？
Good. So you know the truck?
目前只知道是三辆中的一辆 已经追踪好一阵子了
Well, it's one of three. We've been tracking it.
空的
Decoy.
- 你该不会以为蝙蝠侠回来吧？ - 我怎么想并不重要
- You don't really think he's coming back?  - Doesn't matter what I think.
怎么会不重要？你应该把希望寄托在更实际的事物上
Actually, it does. You should put your faith in something a little more real.
- 路线似乎变化不大 - 找到引爆者的身份了吗？
- The routes don't vary much.  - Okay. What about the triggerman?
没线索 应该是唬人的
No leads. It's a bluff.
贝恩不可能把炸弹的控制权交给别人
Bane wouldn't give control of that bomb to someone else.
我们不能冒这个险 在找出引爆者之前
We can't take that chance. Until we have the triggerman,
我们只需追踪炸弹的下落
we just track the device.
这段期间就任凭高谭市被蹂躏？陷入无政府状态？
And meanwhile, Gotham lives under a warlord, like some failed state?
请收回你说的话 这种情况是史无前例的
Dial it back, officer. This situation is unprecedented.
我们不能拿一千多万人的生命当赌注
We can't do anything to risk millions of lives.
你打算向大家报告实情吗？
You gonna tell him what's really going on?
上尉 这事态比你想象中的复杂
Captain, the situation is more complicated than you think.
我们带你去见一个人
There's someone you need to meet.
我来这里寻找制高点的时候 发现那家公司的经营人躲在这里
Came upstairs looking for a vantage point. Found the people who run the corporation.
哪家公司？
What corporation?
韦恩企业
Wayne Enterprises. You good?
福克斯先生 麻烦你跟上尉做个简短的报告
Mr. Fox, would you like to brief the captain?
让泰特小姐说明就可以
Miss Tate's fully aware of the situation.
我是韦恩企业的总裁 这次的事件我们责无旁贷
And as CEO of Wayne Enterprises, I have to take responsibility for it.
- 为什么？ - 因为那是我们制作的
- Why?  - We built it.
炸弹是你们做的？
You built the bomb?
我们制作的是核融合反应器 前所未见的
It was built as a fusion reactor. First of its kind.
贝恩把核心改造成炸弹 并且把它从反应器中卸下来
Bane turned the core into a bomb and removed it from the reactor.
- 要说到重点了 - 随着这个装置的燃料电池劣化
- Here's the important part.  - As the device's fuel cells deteriorate...
它会逐渐变得不稳定
...it becomes increasingly unstable...
最后就会爆炸
...to the point of detonation.
这炸弹是个定时炸弹
This bomb is a time bomb.
23天后就会爆炸 不论贝恩的革命如何进行
And it will go off in 23 days, regardless of Bane's revolution...
不论我们或外界怎么做
...or what we, or the outside world, choose to do.
你的和平计划可能不如想象中的实际
So your plan might not be as practical as you thought.
- 你们能解除炸弹吗？ - 必须把它接回反应器 使它稳定
- Could you disarm it?  - I could reconnect it to the reactor. Stabilize it.
- 我们先离开这个地方再去报告 - 好 走吧
- Let's move from this location and call it in.  - Right. Let's go.
这里由我们接手就可以了 你留下来照顾这些人
No, no, we'll take it from here. You stay and look after these folks.
我们被出卖了
Someone sold us out.
我死也不会说
I'll die before I talk.
那这样如何 上尉？
I'm on your schedule, captain.
楼上有住人
There were people living upstairs.
通通抓去接受审判
Round them up for judgment...
把这三个人吊起来 展示给全世界
...and hang them where the world can see.
他说 那个关键的跳跃 重要的不是体能
He says the leap to freedom is not about strength.
有体能 我才跳得过去
My body makes the jump.
求生是一种是精神 是灵魂
Survival is the spirit. The soul.
我的灵魂已经准备好要逃出去了
My soul is as ready to escape as my body.
你感觉到恐惧吗？
Fear is why you fail.
不 我一点都不害怕
No, I'm not afraid.
我是愤怒
I'm angry.
布鲁斯...
Bruce.
我们为什么会跌倒？
Why do we fall?
你不畏惧死亡
You do not fear death.
你以为这样会使你更坚强？其实只会使你软弱
You think this makes you strong. It makes you weak.
为什么？
Why?
你又如何能够超越自己的速度
How can you move faster than possible...
超越自己的战斗力？
...fight longer than possible...
若是你内心缺少那股最强的动力
...without the most powerful impulse of the spirit?
对死亡的恐惧
The fear of death.
我其实是畏惧死亡的
I do fear death.
我害怕会死在这里
I fear dying in here...
担心我的城市被火焰吞噬
...while my city burns.
却没人拯救它...
There's no one there to save it.
那就爬出去
Then make the climb.
要怎么做？
How?
像那个孩子一样
As the child did...
不要绑绳子
...without the rope.
让恐惧成为你的翅膀
Then fear will find you again.
真是出乎意料
Ah, supplies for your journey?
这样很好
Oh, that's wonderful. That's....
他们在说什么？
What does that mean?
崛起
Rise.
不用
No.
你们抓错人了
No, there's been a mistake!
带我去见贝恩
Take me to Bane!
贝恩在哪里？
I want to see Bane!
肃静
Order!
我要见贝恩
This is a mistake! Where is Bane?
我们没有抓错人 史戴佛先生
There's been no mistake, Mr. Stryver.
你是菲利浦·史戴佛
You are Philip Stryver...
达格工业的副总裁 对吧？
...executive vice president of Daggett Industries...
你这些年来靠着压榨平民百姓血汗
...who for years has been living off the blood and sweat...
享尽荣华富贵
...of people less powerful than him.
打电话给贝恩 我跟你们是一伙的
Call Bane. I am one of you.
我们不受贝恩指挥 这里只是判刑听证会
Bane has no authority here. This is merely a sentencing hearing.
听好 你可以选择
Now, the choice is yours.
放逐或是死刑？
Exile or death!
肃静
Order!
放逐
Exi... Exile.
判刑确定
Sold.
冷汗先生
To the man in the cold sweat.
沿着厚一点的冰层前进
You follow the thick ice.
若是掉进水里 不消几分钟就会冻死
You try to swim, you're dead in minutes.
没有人成功过吧？
Has anyone made it?
他们在哪儿？我们快没时间了
Where are they? It's not like we have a lot of time.
还有多久？
How long?
炸弹明天就会爆炸
The bomb goes off tomorrow.
- 只剩18个小时可用 - 该怎么做？
- We have about 18 hours to do something.  - To do what?
先把GPS装置放到那辆卡车上 再思考如何把炸弹弄下来
To mark the truck. Get a GPS on it so we can start to figure out how to bring it down.
只剩这些人？
That's it?
佛利
Foley.
- 佛利去哪了？ - 你最好不要去街上
- Where's Foley, damn it?  - You shouldn't be out on the streets.
- 吉姆 他不在家 - 在这个城市生死存亡的关键时刻
- Jim, he's not here.  - You let your wife come to the door?
- 你还躲在老婆背后？ - 在厨房里等着
- When the city's under occupation?  - Wait in the kitchen, honey.
你回家做什么？把警察制服埋起来吗？
What did you do, bury your uniform in the backyard?
你也看到他们如何对付那几个特种部队的
You saw what they did to those Special Forces.
你不记得我们以前当巡逻警察的时候
Have you forgotten all the years we were out on patrol?
你心里明白那些暴徒是有多么凶残了吗？
When every gangbanger wanted to plant one as soon as our backs were turned?
现在情况不同 这帮人掌控整个城市 连政府都默许
That was different. These guys run the city. The government's done a deal with them.
他们只是拿贝恩没辙 并没有默许
Bane's got their balls in a vice. That's not a deal.
你如果对贝恩采取行动 引爆者就会按下开关
You move on Bane, the triggerman is gonna hit the button.
你觉得他有可能把炸弹的控制权交给其他人吗？
You think he's given control of that bomb to one of the people?
你真以为他们在搞革命？
You think this is part of some revolution?
只有一个人可以控制炸弹 就是贝恩自己
There's one man with his finger on the button. That's Bane.
听我说 我们最好躲紧一点 等候政府解决一切问题
Look, we've all got to keep our heads down till they can fix this.
- 如果你家人还住这里 - 这件事只能靠我们自己解决
- If you still had a family here...  - This only gets fixed from inside the city!
听着 皮特
Look, Peter.
我不是要求你要成就什么辉煌的事迹
I'm not asking you to walk down Grand in your dress blues,
但是总得有人出来做点事
but something has to be done.
- 抱歉 吉姆 - 躲紧一点？
- Sorry, Jim. I gotta...  - Keep your head down?
明天炸弹爆炸的时候 你要躲到哪里去？
What good's that gonna do when that thing blows?
你根本不知道炸弹会不会爆炸
You don't know that's gonna happen.
听说你需要人手 局长
I hear you're looking for men, commissioner.
让我来帮忙吧？
How about me instead?
泰特小姐 我不能让你身陷危险
Miss Tate, I, uh, can't ask you to do that.
拜托了
Please.
你这个小流氓 你拿了什么？
You little punk! What'd you take?
我什么也没拿
Nothing! I didn't take anything!
敢偷我们的东西？你这小混蛋
You steal from us, you little bastard?
听好了 不准你们在我的地盘撒野
Now, you boys know you can't come into my neighborhood without asking politely.
小子 下次偷东西不要挑这种跑得比你快的对象
Never steal anything from someone you can't outrun, kid.
你真是一个很慷慨的小偷
You're pretty generous for a thief.
- 我以为他们已经杀了你 - 还没呢
- I thought they killed you.  - Not yet.
- 如果你是来要我道歉... - 我不会控诉你的
- If you're expecting an apology, I...  - It wouldn't suit you.
我是来找你帮忙的
I need your help.
我帮你有什么好处？
And why would I help you?
这个"洗底"软件
For this. Clean slate.
你放心把那个交给我吗？
You'd trust me with that?
我把你害得那么惨
After what I did to you?
我承认当时是有一点失望
I'll admit, I was a little let down.
不过我认为你没那么坏 其实 对你而言...
But I still think there's more to you. In fact, I think that for you...
...这只是一个工具
...this isn't just a tool.
你想利用它来洗刷前科 重新做人
It's an escape route. You want to disappear. Start fresh.
- 反正我也逃不出这座岛了 - 我可以帮你逃出去
- I can't even get off this island.  - I can give you a way off...
只要你能帮我找到卢修斯·福克斯
...once you get me to Lucius Fox.
你去帮我调查他被关在哪里 然后把我弄进去
Find out where they're holding him and take me in.
你找福克斯要做什么？
Why do you need Fox?
- 拯救高谭市 - 谁要你拯救了？
- To save the city.  - Who says it needs saving?
我就喜欢这样的高谭市
Maybe I like it this way.
也许你很喜欢
Maybe you do...
但是那炸弹明天就会爆炸
...but tomorrow that bomb's going off.
你又要找你那个厉害的朋友出马吗？
Got your powerful friend on the case?
正是
I'm trying...
但我需要福克斯帮我
...but I need Fox.
它靠近的时候
As it approaches...
就扳这个开关
...flip the switch.
指针超过200就发信号给我 我来标记那辆卡车 没问题吧？
The needle hits 200, you give me the signal, I'll mark the truck. Okay?
警戒! 警戒!
Heads up, heads up.
- 我完成了 - 有卫兵朝你们过去
- I got it.  - Mercenaries on your 6.
不准动! 把手举起来!
Stand still! Keep your hands where we can see them!
高登局长 你被捕了
Commissioner Gordon, you are under arrest.
谁授权你们这么做？
On whose authority?
高谭市的市民
The people of Gotham.
没有律师？没有证人？这根本不是正当法律程序
No lawyer? No witnesses? What sort of due process is this?
你们已经定罪了 现在只是判刑听证会
Your guilt has been determined, this is merely a sentencing hearing.
你要选哪一个？
Now, what will it be?
死刑还是放逐？
Death or exile?
克莱恩 如果你以为我们会心甘情愿地走到那冰上
Crane, if you think we're going out onto that ice willingly...
你脑袋一定有问题
...you have another thing coming.
那就是死刑啰
Death, then.
- 还不都一样 - 好吧
- Looks that way.  - Very well.
判处死刑
Death...
以放逐的方式执行
...by exile.
把她带过来
Bring her to me.
行动要开始了 布莱克说他们已准备好了
Hey, we're going now. Blake says they're ready! Get your gear on!
都听清了吗？行动要开始了
Hey, you hear me? We're going now. Let's do it.
这个人被我们逮个正着 明天有好戏看了
Find this one a spot, got a big day tomorrow.
可不是每天都抓得到布鲁斯·韦恩呢
We all do. It's not every day you bag Bruce Wayne.
- 布鲁斯 - 你没事吧？
- Bruce.  - You okay?
你去度假挑的真不是时候 韦恩先生
Picked a hell of a time to go on vacation, Mr. Wayne.
核心还有多久会点燃？
How long until that core ignites?
- 12个钟头后会爆炸 - 我们得在那之前把它接回反应器
- That bomb goes off in 12 hours.  - Unless we can reconnect it to the reactor.
- 你可以把米兰达救出去吗？ - 今晚不行 抱歉
- Can you get Miranda out of here?  - Not tonight. I'm sorry.
- 尽力做你们该做的 - 今晚我需要你
- Do what's necessary.  - Tonight I need you.
- 要做什么？ - 帮助我重回战局
- What for?  - To get me back in the game.
抱歉扫大家的兴了 他们要我把这些人带走
Sorry to spoil things, boys, but Bane wants these guys to himself.
- 我不会忘记你的 米兰达 - 我懂
- I won't forget about you, Miranda.  - I know.
我喜欢你的新女友 韦恩先生
I like your girlfriend, Mr. Wayne.
他没那么幸运
He should be so lucky.
如果我对贝恩采取行动
Any move I make on Bane or the bomb...
引爆者就会让炸弹爆炸
...the triggerman sets it off.
应该不是无线电或移动电话信号 太容易被干扰了
Well, they won't use radio or cell. Too much interference.
红外线的距离也没那么远
Infrared doesn't have the range.
一定是微爆信号 长波
It'll have to be a microburst. Longwave.
- 有办法阻断吗？ - 可以
- Could you block it?  - Yes.
但我需要用到蝙蝠战机上的EMP飞弹制导系统
But I'll need the EMP cannon guidance mount from the Bat.
还记得你停在哪里吗？
Remember where you parked?
好开吗？
She fly okay?
还不错 虽然没有自动驾驶系统
Yeah, even without the autopilot.
- 多谢啦 - 自动驾驶？那还需要你做什么
- Thanks.  - Autopilot? That's what you're there for.
没人了 快上来
Okay. It's clear. Come on, quick. One at a time.
等等
Wait, wait!
罗斯
Ross!
Ross?
把那里锁起来!
Lock it up.
卧倒
Get down!
你是谁？
Who are you?
点火
Light it up.
- 爸爸 你看 - 亲爱的 快来看
- Dad, check it out.  - Honey, come take a look.
不可能
Impossible.
把她看紧一点
Keep her close.
他会来救她
He'll come for her.
米兰达·泰特在哪里？
Where's Miranda Tate?
贝恩把她带走了
Bane took her.
他占领了市政厅 周围都有他的军队
He's holed up at city hall, surrounded by his army.
这个可以阻断引爆器发送给炸弹的信号
This blocks the remote detonator signal to the bomb.
日出之前把它装上去 我发动的时候 引爆者可能会按下按钮
Get it onto it before sunrise. They might hit the button when it starts.
发动什么？
When what starts?
战争
War.
你漏掉了一个
You missed a spot.
如果你要单枪匹马 记得带面具
If you're working alone, wear a mask.
我不怕人家知道我站出来抵抗恶势力
I'm not afraid to be seen standing up to them.
面具不是要保护你 而是要保护你所爱的人
The mask is not for you. It's to protect the people you care about.
数到五 丢出去
Count to five, then throw.
无意冒犯 你有没有火力强一点的？
No offense, but you got something bigger in that belt?
- 接下来怎么做？ - 全力攻击贝恩
- What now?  - All-out assault on Bane.
但我要你带领民众过桥
But you need to get people across the bridge.
- 为什么？ - 万一我们失败了
- Why?  - In case we fail.
需要留个后路 尽你所能多救一些人
Lead an exodus. Save as many lives as you can.
不需要我留下来帮忙吗？
You don't need me here?
你已经给我一支军队了
You've given me an army.
快去吧
Now go.
谢谢你
Hey, thanks.
不用这么早谢我
Don't thank me yet.
现在不谢 说不定就没机会了
Well, I might not get a chance later.
你不该如此
You shouldn't have.
主要隧道被碎石堵住了
The midtown tunnel's blocked by debris...
帮我用炮弹打开一条通道供民众通行
...but the cannons have enough firepower to make a path for people.
等战争开打的时候再动手
Wait until the fighting begins.
你是为了救你女朋友才开战的吗？
You're gonna wage a war to save your stuck-up girlfriend?
发动 油门
To start it, throttle...
- 我懂啦 - 我们还剩45分钟来拯救这个城市
- I got it.  - We have 45 minutes to save this city.
不对 我还剩45分钟来逃离爆炸半径
No, I've got 45 minutes to get clear of the blast radius.
- 这场战争你根本毫无胜算 - 如果你愿意帮忙 我或许能成功
- You don't stand a chance against these guys.  - With your help, I might.
我会帮你打通隧道 然后就走人
I'll open that tunnel, then I'm gone.
你不是那样的人
There's more to you than that.
抱歉我总是让你失望
Sorry to keep letting you down.
跟我一起走吧
Come with me.
救你自己一命
Save yourself.
你对这些人不再有所亏欠
You don't owe these people any more.
你已为他们奉献出了一切
You've given them everything.
不是一切
Not everything.
还不够
Not yet.
快点解散
Disperse!
不然就开火了
Disperse or be fired upon!
我们才是这个城市的正牌警察
There's only one police in this town.
开火
Open fire.
- 来了 - 预备
- Here it comes!  - Get ready!
你是回来这里陪葬的吗？
So you came back to die with your city.
不 我是来制止你的
No. I came back to stop you.
现在...
Now!
这不可能
That's impossible.
去第五街
Cut over to Fifth!
快上巴士 快去
Here you go. Get on the bus. Go ahead.
你跟我来 你也是
You, come with me. You too.
你 你 你 到这边来
Hey, you, you, and you, come here, come here.
其他人全部上车
Everyone else get on the bus, okay?
你们几个去挨家挨户敲门 告诉大家炸弹要爆炸了
You guys, you go knock on doors and spread the word, okay?
叫大家从南街的隧道逃走 或是过桥逃走
The bomb is gonna go off. Get out by the South Street tunnel or over the bridge.
走两个街区就回到巴士上 听懂了吗？
You do two blocks and you get back to the bus, all right?
快去吧
Go, go, go!
他回来了吗？
Is he back?
小心点 快去
Keep your eyes open. Go, go.
守住门口
Cover the doors!
引爆器在哪儿？
Where's your trigger?!
在哪里？
Where is it?!
你根本没把引爆器交给别人 对吧？
You'd never give it to an ordinary citizen!
引爆器在哪？
Where is it? Where's your trigger?
在哪里？
Where is it?! Where is it?!
告诉我引爆器在哪里
Tell me where the trigger is.
然后 我就让你领死
Then you have my permission to die.
我明明打断了你的背
I broke you.
你是怎么回来这里的？
How have you come back?
你以为只有你有那个本事逃出来吗？
You think you're the only one who could learn the strength to escape?
引爆器在哪里？
Where's the trigger?
我从没逃出来过
But I never escaped.
但是那个孩子
But the child.
忍者大师的孩子不是逃出来了吗？
The child of Ra's Al Ghul made the climb.
他不是忍者大师的孩子
But he's not the child of Ra's Al Ghul.
我才是
I am.
虽然我不是普通人
And though I'm not ordinary...
但我也是本市的市民
...I am a citizen.
米兰达
Miranda?
为什么这么做？
Why?
塔莉亚
Talia.
那是我母亲去世前给我取的名字
My mother named me Talia, before she was killed...
若不是贝恩守护我 我早就和我母亲一起死了
...the way I would have been killed, if not for my protector Bane.
永别了
Goodbye.
我逃出来后
I climbed out of the pit.
找到我的父亲
I found my father...
带他回去复仇
...and brought him back to exact terrible vengeance.
可是迟了一步
But by that time...
囚犯和狱医对我的守护者做了可怕的事
...the prisoners and doctor had done their work to my friend. My protector.
我们接受影武者联盟的训练
The League took us in. Trained us.
但我父亲不接收贝恩
But my father could not accept Bane.
他视贝恩为怪物
He saw only a monster.
让他忘不了自己的妻子在那人间炼狱中惨死
His very existence was a reminder of the hell he'd left his wife to die in.
所以他把贝恩逐出了影武者联盟
He excommunicated Bane from the League of Shadows.
他唯一犯的错就是他爱我
His only crime was that he loved me.
我原本无法原谅我父亲
I could not forgive my father.
直到你杀死了他
Until you murdered him.
他试图杀害上千万的无辜民众
He was trying to kill millions of innocent people.
高谭市的市民配不上"无辜"二字 布鲁斯
Innocent is a strong word to throw around Gotham, Bruce.
我要完成我父亲的遗愿
I honor my father by finishing his work.
为了报杀父之仇 我耐心等候了这么多年
Vengeance against the man who killed him is simply a reward for my patience.
明白了吗？
You see...
就是那把慢慢琢磨的刀
...it's the slow knife...the knife that takes its time.
那把静静等候却未曾遗忘的刀
The knife that waits years without forgetting...
才能锥心刺骨
...then slips quietly between the bones.
才能让你痛彻心扉
That's the knife that cuts deepest.
拜托不要
Please.
你的刀可能磨得太慢了
Maybe your knife was too slow.
有人攻击卡车
The truck is under attack.
高登？是你教他阻断引爆器的信号
Gordon. You gave him a way to block my signal.
没关系
No matter.
他只是帮高谭市多争取11分钟的时间
He's bought Gotham 11 minutes.
快下来
Come on!
这边走
This way!
不准动 你在做什么？
Stay there! What are you doing?
我是布莱克警探 我要带大家去安全的地方
Blake, MCU! I'm getting these boys to safety!
你们会害死所有人
You'll get us all killed!
只要有人走过这座桥 贝恩就会把高谭市炸掉
If anyone crosses this bridge, they'll blow the city!
反正炸弹快爆炸了 请你们立刻开放这座桥
It's gonna blow anyway! We need to open this bridge, now!
你往前一步 我们就对你开枪
Detective, if you take one step forward we will shoot you!
你往前两步 我们就炸断这座桥
If you take two steps forward, we will blow the bridge!
先回车上等我好吗？回车上
Okay, go back by the bus and wait for me, all right? Go back and wait.
去准备护送部队 在爆炸之前 我们一定要把炸弹看好
Prepare a convoy. We must secure the bomb until it detonates.
不要杀他 让他亲身感受那股炙热
Don't kill him, I want him to feel the heat.
1200万灵魂燃烧的火焰 你失败了
Feel the fire of 12 million souls. You failed.
永别了 我的朋友
Goodbye, my friend.
永别了
Goodbye.
继续前进 把他们逼向台阶
Keep moving forward! Flank them at the stairs!
扫射
Shoot them.
通通杀掉
Shoot them all.
你应该心知肚明 我现在就要把你解决掉
We both know that I have to kill you now.
只好请你自己想象那股炙热的火焰了
You'll just have to imagine the fire.
关于那个"不准开枪"的原则...
About the whole no-guns thing...
我实在没办法像你有那么坚定的信念
...I'm not sure I feel as strongly about it as you do.
开到它旁边
Pull up.
保持这个位置
Stay level.
我们必须逼他们把卡车开往反应器的入口
We have to force that convoy east to the entrance to the reactor.
你从地面上进行 我也会过去 走吧
I need you on the ground, I'll be in the air. Go.
情势有所改变 先前的命令已经不适用了
The situation has changed. Your orders are out of date.
我跟你们一样都是警察 现在我要走过去了
I'm a cop, like you, and I'm walking out there.
请不要对我开枪
Please do not shoot me!
打他的脚
Shoot at his feet.
没有什么比空中优势更棒的了
Nothing like a little air superiority.
警探 请止步
Detective! Please stop!
拜托 停下来
Please, detective! Stop!
不要过来
Stop walking!
把桥炸断 炸掉
Blow it! Do it!
你们要把炸弹带过来这里 还剩十分钟
You have to get that bomb here. You've got 10 minutes.
他们正把我们逼向反应器的入口
They're pushing us to the entrance of the reactor.
想把核心重新接回去
They're gonna try to reconnect the core.
你这个大笨蛋
You idiots!
你个王八蛋
You sons of bitches!
大家都要被你害死了
You're killing us!
只会死守命令
Yeah, follow your orders!
好了 孩子们 大家手牵手围个圆圈
All right, boys. Get in a circle. Bow your heads.
他撑不了多久
It's on my side.
大家回车上坐好 快点
Hey, Father! Let's get everyone back on the bus, okay? Go, go, go!
- 都回车上 - 我们已经无处可逃了
- Back on the bus!  - There's nowhere to go.
快上车
On the bus!
你们要把卡车逼向东边
You've got to turn the truck east!
不要转弯
Stay straight!
快来帮我 我们在上面绑一条绳索
Give me a hand! We can get a cable on it!
福克斯有教我如何修改反应器
Fox showed me how to override the reactor.
糟了
Oh, dear.
包括紧急洪水的设定
Including the emergency flood.
你们不可能阻止炸弹爆炸的
There's no way this bomb will be stopped.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
做好爆炸气流的防护 大家不会有事的
Protection from the blast. We're gonna be all right!
那是原子弹
It's an atom bomb!
你想看着大家抱憾而死吗？快点
Think they need to hear that? Let them die without hope? Come on!
准备受死吧
Prepare yourselves.
我已经完成了我父亲的遗愿
My father's work is done.
- 你要做什么？ - 我可以把它带到海上
- What are you doing?  - I can get it out over the bay!
你可以设定飞到海上然后就跳机吗？
Set it to fly out over the water, then eject?
没有自动驾驶
No autopilot.
你本来可以一走了之 但你却选择回来这里
You could've gone anywhere, been anything. But you came back here.
你也是
So did you.
我们这两个大傻瓜
I guess we're both suckers.
- 我本来不想问你的真实身份 - 很好
- I never cared who you were.  - And you were right.
但是人们有权知道谁是拯救他们的英雄
Shouldn't the people know the hero who saved them?
任何人都可以是英雄
A hero can be anyone.
哪怕只是做一个简单的举动
Even a man doing something as simple and reassuring...
为无助的小男孩披上外套 让他知道...
...as putting a coat around a young boy's shoulders to let him know...
人生还可以继续下去
...the world hadn't ended.
布鲁斯·韦恩？
Bruce Wayne?
快点 你也快点 神父
Come on! There you go! Okay, you too. Come on, Father.
快低下头 爆炸了
Hey, heads down! This is it!
- 不是 - 不是 那是蝙蝠侠
- No.  - No, that's Batman!
爆炸了
That's detonation!
是在海上 不在城市里
It's out over the bay! Clear of the city!
"我看见一座美丽的城市"
"I see a beautiful city...
"和一群杰出的民众"
...and a brilliant people...
"从这个深渊中升起"
...rising from this abyss.
"我看见我为之献出生命的人们"
I see the lives for which I lay down my life...
"过着和平 有益 繁荣和幸福的生活"
...peaceful, useful, prosperous and happy.
"我看见我在他们的心中..."
I see that I hold a sanctuary in their hearts...
"和世世代代后裔的心中..."
...and in the hearts of their descendants...
"占有神圣的地位"
...generations hence.
"我现在所做的事"
It is a far, far better thing that I do...
"远比我所做过的一切都美好"
...than I have ever done.
"我现在将获得的休息"
It is a far, far better rest that I go to...
"远比我所经历的一切都安详"
...than I have ever known."
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我让您失望了
I failed you.
您这么信任我...
You trusted me...
而我却辜负了您
...and I failed you.
你可以改变心意吗？
Can I change your mind...
关于辞职的事
...about quitting the force?
记得你曾跟我说过体制成为枷锁的事吗？
You know what you said about structures becoming shackles?
你说的很对 而我无法忍受这种不公不义
You were right, and I can't take it. The injustice.
人们永远不会知道是谁拯救了这个城市
I mean, no one's ever gonna know who saved an entire city.
会知道的
They know.
是蝙蝠侠
It was the Batman.
韦恩先生的遗嘱没有依减少的资产而做修订
Mr. Wayne's will was not amended to reflect his more modest estate.
但仍有极为可观的财产可供处分
Nonetheless, there are considerable assets to dispose of.
其宅邸内物品出售的所得将用来清偿债务
The contents of the house are to be sold to settle the estate's accounts...
余额全数归于阿福·潘尼华斯
...and the remainder is left in its entirety to Alfred J. Pennyworth.
房屋和土地遗赠给高谭市
The house and grounds are left to the city of Gotham on condition that...
条件是不得拆除、变更或行其他干涉之事
...they never be demolished, altered or otherwise interfered with...
并且只能做为唯一指定用途使用：
...and that they shall be used for one purpose, and one purpose only:
本市的受虐儿童及孤儿收容中心
The housing and care of the city's at-risk and orphaned children.
我的办事员会协助处理其他遗留书信和指示
My clerk can help with the smaller correspondences and instructions.
约翰·布莱克
Blake, John.
- 没有你的名字 - 那看看我的本名
- Nothing here.  - Uh, try my legal name.
你应该使用你的本名 这名字很好听
You should use your full name. I like that name.
- 罗宾 - 谢谢
- Robin.  - Thanks.
为什么要继续在这软件上耗费心思？
Why worry about the stabilization software?
这种自动驾驶系统很早就被淘汰了
This entire autopilot system's completely obsolete.
我只是想知道为什么我修不好
Please, I just need to know what I could've done to fix it.
可是 福克斯先生 明明六个月前已经修好了
But, Mr. Fox, it's already been fixed. Software patch. Six months ago.
可以查查是谁修好的吗？
Check the ID on the patch.
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
- 找到缺漏物品了吗？ - 还没
- Any news on the missing item?  - Not yet.
一定要想尽办法把它找出来
They better leave no stone unturned.
我们不能把那条珍珠项链列为遗失
We can't leave a string of pearls on the manifest as lost.
《蝙蝠侠：黑暗骑士崛起》